<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="1"/>
<context>
a sister, to bestow her affection and confidence on one who ought to have been nothing to her but the object of distant civility. From situation, Mrs Clay was, in Lady Russell's estimate, a very unequal, and in her character she <head>believed</head> a very dangerous companion;and a removal that would leave Mrs Clay behind, and bring a choice of more suitable intimates within Miss Elliot's reach, was therefore an object of first-rate importance.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="1"/>
<context>
have been possible to withstand her father's ill-will,though unsoftened by one kind word or look on the part of her sister; but Lady Russell, whom she had always loved and relied on, could not, with such steadiness of opinion, and such tenderness of manner, be continually advising her in vain.  She was persuaded to <head>believe</head> the engagement a wrong thing:  indiscreet, improper, hardly capable of success, and not deserving it.  But it was not a merely selfish caution, under which she acted, in putting an end to it.  Had she not imagined herself consulting his good, even more than her own,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="1"/>
<context>
she was persuaded that under every disadvantage of disapprobation at home, and every anxiety attending his profession, all their probable fears, delays, and disappointments, she should yet have been a happier woman in maintaining the engagement, than she had been in the sacrifice of it; and this, she fully <head>believed</head>, had the usual share, had even more than the usual share of all such solicitudes and suspense been theirs, without reference to the actual results of their case, which, as it happened, would have bestowed earlier prosperity than could be reasonably calculated on.  All his sanguine expectations,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="1"/>
<context>
from whatever it sprung; and in the event of Admiral Croft's really taking Kellynch Hall, she rejoiced anew over the conviction which had always been most grateful to her, of the past being known to those three only among her connexions, by whom no syllable, she <head>believed</head>, would ever be whispered, and in the trust that among his, the brother only with whom he had been residing, had received any information of their short-lived engagement.  That brother had been long removed from the country and being a sensible man, and, moreover, a single man at the time, she had a fond dependence on no human creature's
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="1"/>
<context>
She had never been staying there before, without being struck by it, or without wishing that other Elliots could have her advantage in seeing how unknown, or unconsidered there, were the affairs which at Kellynch Hall were treated as of such general publicity and pervading interest; yet, with all this experience, she <head>believed</head> she must now submit to feel that another lesson, in the art of knowing our own nothingness beyond our own circle, was become necessary for her; for certainly, coming as she did, with a heart full of the subject which had been completely occupying both houses in Kellynch for many weeks,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Known to have some influence with her sister, she was continually requested, or at least receiving hints to exert it, beyond what was practicable. "I wish you could persuade Mary not to be always fancying herself ill," was Charles's language; and, in an unhappy mood, thus spoke Mary: "I do <head>believe</head> if Charles were to see me dying, he would not think there was anything the matter with me.  I am sure, Anne, if you would, you might persuade him that I really am very ill--a great deal worse than I ever own."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="1"/>
<context>
with the other family, since there was neither superior affection, confidence, nor employment in the cottage, to be interrupted by it, was rather an advantage.  It was certainly carried nearly as far as possible, for they met every morning, and hardly ever spent an evening asunder; but she <head>believed</head> they should not have done so well without the sight of Mr and Mrs Musgrove's respectable forms in the usual places, or without the talking, laughing, and singing of their daughters. She played a great deal better than either of the Miss Musgroves,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="1"/>
<context>
She would have liked to know how he felt as to a meeting.Perhaps indifferent, if indifference could exist under such circumstances. He must be either indifferent or unwilling.  Had he wished ever to see her again, he need not have waited till this time; he would have done what she could not but <head>believe</head> that in his place she should have done long ago, when events had been early giving him the independence which alone had been wanting. Her brother and sister came back delighted with their new acquaintance,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="1"/>
<context>
and there must be intercourse between the two families. This was against her; but on the other hand, he spent so much of his time at Uppercross, that in removing thence she might be considered rather as leaving him behind, than as going towards him; and, upon the whole, she <head>believed</head> she must, on this interesting question, be the gainer, almost as certainly as in her change of domestic society, in leaving poor Mary for Lady Russell.She wished it might be possible for her to avoid ever seeing
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="1"/>
<context>
mourning her loss.  They had been a year or two waiting for fortune and promotion.  Fortune came, his prize-money as lieutenant being great; promotion, too, came at last; but Fanny Harville did not live to know it. She had died the preceding summer while he was at sea.  Captain Wentworth <head>believed</head> it impossible for man to be more attached to woman than poor Benwick had been to Fanny Harville, or to be more deeply afflicted under the dreadful change.  He considered his disposition as of the sort which must suffer heavily, uniting very strong feelings with quiet, serious, and retiring manners, and a decided taste for reading,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="1"/>
<context>
"I love your indignation," said he; "it is very natural. But here you are in Bath, and the object is to be established here with all the credit and dignity which ought to belong to Sir Walter Elliot. You talk of being proud; I am called proud, I know, and I shall not wish to <head>believe</head> myself otherwise; for our pride, if investigated, would have the same object, I have no doubt, though the kind may seem a little different.  In one point, I am sure, my dear cousin," (he continued, speaking lower, though there was no one else in the room) "in one point, I am sure, we must feel alike.  We must feel that
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Her accommodations were limited to a noisy parlour, and a dark bedroom behind, with no possibility of moving from one to the other without assistance, which there was only one servant in the house to afford, and she never quitted the house but to be conveyed into the warm bath. Yet, in spite of all this, Anne had reason to <head>believe</head> that she had moments only of languor and depression, to hours of occupation and enjoyment.  How could it be?  She watched, observed, reflected, and finally determined that this was not a case of fortitude or of resignation only.  A submissive spirit might be patient,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="1"/>
<context>
to be au fait as to the newest modes of being trifling and silly. To me, who live so much alone, her conversation, I assure you, is a treat." Anne, far from wishing to cavil at the pleasure, replied, "I can easily <head>believe</head> it.  Women of that class have great opportunities, and if they are intelligent may be well worth listening to. Such varieties of human nature as they are in the habit of witnessing! And it is not merely in its follies, that they are well read; for they see it occasionally under every circumstance that can be
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="1"/>
<context>
He was preparing only to bow and pass on, but her gentle "How do you do?" brought him out of the straight line to stand near her, and make enquiries in return, in spite of the formidable father and sister in the back ground. Their being in the back ground was a support to Anne; she knew nothing of their looks, and felt equal to everything which she <head>believed</head> right to be done.While they were speaking, a whispering between her father and Elizabeth caught her ear.  She could not distinguish, but she must guess the subject;
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="1"/>
<context>
"The name of Anne Elliot," said he, "has long had an interesting sound to me. Very long has it possessed a charm over my fancy; and, if I dared, I would breathe my wishes that the name might never change." Such, she <head>believed</head>, were his words; but scarcely had she received their sound, than her attention was caught by other sounds immediately behind her, which rendered every thing else trivial. Her father and Lady Dalrymple were speaking.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="1"/>
<context>
"No!" he replied impressively, "there is nothing worth my staying for;" and he was gone directly.Jealousy of Mr Elliot!  It was the only intelligible motive. Captain Wentworth jealous of her affection!  Could she have <head>believed</head> it a week ago; three hours ago!  For a moment the gratification was exquisite. But, alas! there were very different thoughts to succeed. How was such jealousy to be quieted?  How was the truth to reach him? How, in all the peculiar disadvantages of their respective situations,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="1"/>
<context>
of last night might afford:  not Mr Elliot; it is not Mr Elliot that--" She stopped, regretting with a deep blush that she had implied so much; but less would hardly have been sufficient.  Mrs Smith would hardly have <head>believed</head> so soon in Mr Elliot's failure, but from the perception of there being a somebody else.  As it was, she instantly submitted, and with all the semblance of seeing nothing beyond; and Anne, eager to escape farther notice, was impatient to know why Mrs Smith should have fancied she was to marry Mr Elliot; where she could have
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="1"/>
<context>
to be officious, to be giving bad impressions, making mischief. Even the smooth surface of family union seems worth preserving, though there may be nothing durable beneath.  However, I have determined; I think I am right; I think you ought to be made acquainted with Mr Elliot's real character.  Though I fully <head>believe</head> that, at present, you have not the smallest intention of accepting him, there is no saying what may happen.  You might, some time or other, be differently affected towards him.  Hear the truth, therefore, now, while you are unprejudiced.  Mr Elliot is a man without heart
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="1"/>
<context>
for what is all this but assertion, and you shall have proof." "Indeed, my dear Mrs Smith, I want none," cried Anne.  "You have asserted nothing contradictory to what Mr Elliot appeared to be some years ago. This is all in confirmation, rather, of what we used to hear and <head>believe</head>. I am more curious to know why he should be so different now." "But for my satisfaction, if you will have the goodness to ring for Mary; stay:  I am sure you will have the still greater goodness of
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="1"/>
<context>
"Dear Smith,--I have received yours.  Your kindness almost overpowers me. I wish nature had made such hearts as yours more common, but I have lived three-and-twenty years in the world, and have seen none like it. At present, <head>believe</head> me, I have no need of your services, being in cash again.  Give me joy:  I have got rid of Sir Walter and Miss. They are gone back to Kellynch, and almost made me swear to visit them this summer; but my first visit to Kellynch will be with a surveyor, to tell me how to bring it with best advantage to the hammer.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="1"/>
<context>
forgot all about Lyme."To pacify Mary, and perhaps screen her own embarrassment, Anne did move quietly to the window.  She was just in time to ascertain that it really was Mr Elliot, which she had never <head>believed</head>, before he disappeared on one side, as Mrs Clay walked quickly off on the other; and checking the surprise which she could not but feel at such an appearance of friendly conference between two persons of totally opposite interest, she calmly said, "Yes, it is Mr Elliot,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="1"/>
<context>
but not to Anne.  She could think only of the invitation she had with such astonishment witnessed, and of the manner in which it had been received; a manner of doubtful meaning, of surprise rather than gratification, of polite acknowledgement rather than acceptance. She knew him; she saw disdain in his eye, and could not venture to <head>believe</head> that he had determined to accept such an offering, as an atonement for all the insolence of the past.  Her spirits sank.  He held the card in his hand after they were gone, as if deeply considering it.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Who can be in doubt of what followed?  When any two young people take it into their heads to marry, they are pretty sure by perseverance to carry their point, be they ever so poor, or ever so imprudent, or ever so little likely to be necessary to each other's ultimate comfort. This may be bad morality to conclude with, but I <head>believe</head> it to be truth; and if such parties succeed, how should a Captain Wentworth and an Anne Elliot, with the advantage of maturity of mind, consciousness of right, and one independent fortune between them, fail of bearing down every opposition?  They might in fact,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="1"/>
<context>
strong felicity.  She had but two friends in the world to add to his list, Lady Russell and Mrs Smith.  To those, however, he was very well disposed to attach himself.  Lady Russell, in spite of all her former transgressions, he could now value from his heart.  While he was not obliged to say that he <head>believed</head> her to have been right in originally dividing them, he was ready to say almost everything else in her favour, and as for Mrs Smith, she had claims of various kinds to recommend her quickly and permanently.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="1"/>
<context>
from a tree served as a spear; a thick stick in his strong arms became a powerful club. Later, perhaps, came the use of a hard stone such as flint, which could be chipped into the forms of arrowheads, axes, and spear tips. The first stone implements were so rude in shape that it is difficult to <head>believe</head> them of human workmanship. They may have been made several hundred thousand years ago. After countless centuries of slow advance, savages learned to fasten wooden handles to their stone tools and weapons and also to use such materials as jade and granite, which could be ground and polished into a variety of forms. Stone implements continued to be made
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="1"/>
<context>
We have seen how steadily since the days of the Gracchi the Roman state had been moving toward the rule of one man. Marius, Sulla, and Pompey each represent a step in the direction of monarchy. Yet there were still able and patriotic leaders at Rome who <head>believed</head> in the old order of things and tried their best to uphold the fast-perishing republic. No republican statesman was more devoted to the constitution than Cicero. A native of Arpinum, the same Italian town which had already given birth to Marius, Cicero came to Rome a youth without wealth or family influence. He made
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Several centuries before the rise of Christianity many Greek thinkers began to feel a growing dissatisfaction with the crude faith that had come down to them from prehistoric times. They found it more and more difficult to <head>believe</head> in the Olympian deities, who were fashioned like themselves and had all the faults of mortal men. [10] An adulterous Zeus, a bloodthirsty Ares, and a scolding Hera, as Homer represents them, were hardly divinities that a cultured Greek could love and worship. For educated Romans, also, the rites and ceremonies of the ancient religion came
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="1"/>
<context>
But in closing our survey of the Germanic invasions we need to dwell on the forces that made for progress, rather than on those that made for decline. Classical civilization, we have already found reason to <head>believe</head>, [17] had begun to decay long before the Germans broke up the empire. The Germans came, as Christianity had come, only to hasten the process of decay. Each of these influences, in turn, worked to build up the fabric of a new society on the ruins of the old. First Christianity infused the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="1"/>
<context>
solitary vigils, practices perhaps suggested to him by the example of Christian hermits. [3] During these lonely hours in the desert strange scenes passed before his eyes and strange voices sounded in his ears. At first Mohammed thought that evil spirits possessed him, but Khadija encouraged him to <head>believe</head> that his visions were a revelation from another world. One day, so he declared, God's messenger, the archangel Gabriel, appeared to him and bade him preach a new religion to the Arabs. It was very simple, but in its simplicity lay its strength: "There is no god but God, and Mohammed is the prophet of God."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="1"/>
<context>
burden of proof lay on the accused, who had to clear himself of the charge, if he could do so. In one form of trial it was enough for him to declare his innocence under oath, and then to bring in several "oath- helpers," sometimes relatives, but more often neighbors, who swore that they <head>believed</head> him to be telling the truth. The number of these "oath- helpers" varied according to the seriousness of the crime and the rank of the accused. This method was hardly as unsatisfactory as it seems to be, for a person of evil reputation might not be able to secure the required number of friends who would commit perjury on his behalf. To take an oath
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="1"/>
<context>
time many offenders went unpunished, especially if they were so powerful that no private individual dared accuse them. Henry provided that when the king's justices came to a county court a number of selected men should be put upon their oath and required to give the names of any persons whom they knew or <head>believed</head> to be guilty of crimes. Such persons were then to be arrested and tried. This "grand jury," as it came to be called, thus had the public duty of making accusations, whether its members felt any personal interest in the matter or not.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The numerous trials and executions for witchcraft form a dark page in history. Thousands of harmless old men and women were put to death on the charge of being leagued with the Devil. Even the most intelligent and humane people <head>believed</head> in the reality of witchcraft and found a justification for its punishment in the Scriptural command, "Thou shalt not suffer a witch to live." [32] The witch epidemic which broke out in America during the seventeenth century, reaching its height at Salem, Massachusetts, was simply a reflection of the European fear and hatred of
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="1"/>
<context>
speculations of theologians, and the excessive reliance which common people had on pilgrimages, festivals, relics, and other aids to devotion. So great was the demand for this work that it went through twenty-seven large editions during the author's lifetime. Erasmus and others like him were loyal sons of the Church, but they <head>believed</head> they could best serve her interests by effecting her reform. Some men went further, however, and demanded wholesale changes in Catholic belief and worship. These men were the heretics.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="1"/>
<context>
In spite of all measures of repression heretics were not uncommon during the later Middle Ages. Some heretical movements spread over entire communities. The most important was that of the Albigenses, so called from the town of Albi in southern France, where many of them lived. Their doctrines are not well known, but they seem to have <head>believed</head> in the existence of two gods--one good (whose son was Christ), the other evil (whose son was Satan). The Albigenses even set up a rival church, with its priests, bishops, and councils.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="1"/>
<context>
congregation, of men and women brought together in the bonds of a common religious faith. By one of the strange fortunes of history, this institution, founded in the early days of Christianity, proved to be a potent force in the origin and growth of self-government in a land far away from Galilee. "And the multitude of them that <head>believed</head> were of one heart and of one soul," we are told in the Acts describing the Church at Jerusalem. "We are knit together as a body in a most sacred covenant of the Lord ... by virtue of which we hold ourselves strictly tied to all care of each other's good and of the whole," wrote John Robinson
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="1"/>
<context>
other denominations, that principle was strictly applied in Rhode Island. There, under the leadership of Roger Williams, liberty in matters of conscience was established in the beginning. Maryland, by granting in 1649 freedom to those who professed to <head>believe</head> in Jesus Christ, opened its gates to all Christians; and Pennsylvania, true to the tenets of the Friends, gave freedom of conscience to those "who confess and acknowledge the one Almighty and Eternal God to be the creator, upholder, and ruler of the World." By one circumstance or
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The methods employed by this board were varied. All laws passed by American legislatures came before it for review as a matter of routine. If it found an act unsatisfactory, it recommended to the king the exercise of his veto power, known as the royal disallowance. Any person who <head>believed</head> his personal or property rights injured by a colonial law could be heard by the board in person or by attorney; in such cases it was the practice to hear at the same time the agent of the colony so involved. The royal veto power over colonial legislation was not, therefore, a formal affair, but was constantly employed on the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="1"/>
<context>
public debate, and deeply interested in science and philosophy, Jefferson was not very well fitted for the strenuous life of political contest. Nevertheless, he was an ambitious and shrewd negotiator. He was also by honest opinion and matured conviction the exact opposite of Hamilton. The latter <head>believed</head> in a strong, active, "high-toned" government, vigorously compelling in all its branches. Jefferson looked upon such government as dangerous to the liberties of citizens and openly avowed his faith in the desirability of occasional popular uprisings. Hamilton distrusted the people. "Your people is a great
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="1"/>
<context>
further restricted by religious provisions. No single sect was powerful enough to dominate after the Revolution, but, for the most part, Catholics and Jews were either disfranchised or excluded from office. North Carolina and Georgia denied the ballot to any one who was not a Protestant. Delaware withheld it from all who did not <head>believe</head> in the Trinity and the inspiration of the Scriptures. Massachusetts and Maryland limited it to Christians. Virginia and New York, advanced for their day, made no discrimination in government on account of religious opinion.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="1"/>
<context>
In Pennsylvania, a leader in local affairs cried out against a plan to remove the taxpaying limitation on the suffrage: "What does the delegate propose? To place the vicious vagrant, the wandering Arabs, the Tartar hordes of our large cities on the level with the virtuous and good man?" In Virginia, Jefferson himself had first <head>believed</head> in property qualifications and had feared with genuine alarm the "mobs of the great cities." It was near the end of the eighteenth century before he accepted the idea of manhood suffrage. Even then he was unable to convince the constitution-makers of his own state. "It is not an idle
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="2"/>
<context>
all the expedition which the most comprehensive retrenchments could secure, and saw no dignity in anything short of it. She wanted it to be prescribed, and felt as a duty.  She rated Lady Russell's influence highly; and as to the severe degree of self-denial which her own conscience prompted, she <head>believed</head> there might be little more difficulty in persuading them to a complete, than to half a reformation.  Her knowledge of her father and Elizabeth inclined her to think that the sacrifice of one pair of horses would be hardly less painful than of both, and so on,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="2"/>
<context>
over London had of course been given all their weight:  its more convenient distance from Kellynch, only fifty miles, and Lady Russell's spending some part of every winter there; and to the very great satisfaction of Lady Russell, whose first views on the projected change had been for Bath, Sir Walter and Elizabeth were induced to <head>believe</head> that they should lose neither consequence nor enjoyment by settling there. Lady Russell felt obliged to oppose her dear Anne's known wishes. It would be too much to expect Sir Walter to descend into a small house
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="2"/>
<context>
He had distinguished himself, and early gained the other step in rank, and must now, by successive captures, have made a handsome fortune. She had only navy lists and newspapers for her authority, but she could not doubt his being rich; and, in favour of his constancy, she had no reason to <head>believe</head> him married.How eloquent could Anne Elliot have been! how eloquent, at least,were her wishes on the side of early warm attachment, and a cheerful confidence in futurity, against that over-anxious caution which
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Charles Musgrove was civil and agreeable; in sense and temper he was undoubtedly superior to his wife, but not of powers, or conversation, or grace, to make the past, as they were connected together, at all a dangerous contemplation; though, at the same time, Anne could <head>believe</head>, with Lady Russell, that a more equal match might have greatly improved him; and that a woman of real understanding might have given more consequence to his character, and more usefulness, rationality, and elegance to his habits and pursuits.  As it was, he did nothing with much zeal, but sport; and his time was otherwise
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="2"/>
<context>
as ever were seen, poor little dears! without partiality; but Mrs Charles knows no more how they should be treated--! Bless me! how troublesome they are sometimes.  I assure you, Miss Anne, it prevents my wishing to see them at our house so often as I otherwise should.  I <head>believe</head> Mrs Charles is not quite pleased with my not inviting them oftener; but you know it is very bad to have children with one that one is obligated to be checking every moment; "don't do this," and "don't do that;"  or that one can only keep in tolerable order by more cake than is good for them."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="2"/>
<context>
and yet Henrietta had sometimes the air of being divided between them. Anne longed for the power of representing to them all what they were about, and of pointing out some of the evils they were exposing themselves to. She did not attribute guile to any.  It was the highest satisfaction to her to <head>believe</head> Captain Wentworth not in the least aware of the pain he was occasioning.  There was no triumph, no pitiful triumph in his manner.  He had, probably, never heard, and never thought of any claims of Charles Hayter.  He was only wrong in accepting the attentions (for accepting must be the word) of two young women at once.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="2"/>
<context>
They were indebted, the next day, to Charles Hayter, for all the minute knowledge of Louisa, which it was so essential to obtain every twenty-four hours.  He made it his business to go to Lyme, and his account was still encouraging.  The intervals of sense and consciousness were <head>believed</head> to be stronger.  Every report agreed in Captain Wentworth's appearing fixed in Lyme.Anne was to leave them on the morrow, an event which they all dreaded."What should they do without her?  They were wretched comforters
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="2"/>
<context>
"Well, whenever it suits you.  You can slip in from the shrubbery at any time; and there you will find we keep our umbrellas hanging up by that door.  A good place is not it?  But," (checking himself), "you will not think it a good place, for yours were always kept in the butler's room.  Ay, so it always is, I <head>believe</head>. One man's ways may be as good as another's, but we all like our own best. And so you must judge for yourself, whether it would be better for you to go about the house or not."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="2"/>
<context>
But Mary did not give into it very graciously, whether from not considering Captain Benwick entitled by birth and situation to be in love with an Elliot, or from not wanting to <head>believe</head> Anne a greater attraction to Uppercross than herself, must be left to be guessed.  Anne's good-will, however, was not to be lessened by what she heard.  She boldly acknowledged herself flattered, and continued her enquiries.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="2"/>
<context>
and when very young himself.  How her temper and understanding might bear the investigation of his present keener time of life was another concern and rather a fearful one.  Most earnestly did she wish that he might not be too nice, or too observant if Elizabeth were his object; and that Elizabeth was disposed to <head>believe</head> herself so, and that her friend Mrs Clay was encouraging the idea, seemed apparent by a glance or two between them, while Mr Elliot's frequent visits were talked of.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="2"/>
<context>
of its being very ungenteel to be curious. "The notions of a young man of one or two and twenty," said he, "as to what is necessary in manners to make him quite the thing, are more absurd, I <head>believe</head>, than those of any other set of beings in the world.  The folly of the means they often employ is only to be equalled by the folly of what they have in view." But he must not be addressing his reflections to Anne alone:
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="2"/>
<context>
may be of use in diverting his thoughts from those who are beneath him."He looked, as he spoke, to the seat which Mrs Clay had been lately occupying:  a sufficient explanation of what he particularly meant; and though Anne could not <head>believe</head> in their having the same sort of pride, she was pleased with him for not liking Mrs Clay; and her conscience admitted that his wishing to promote her father's getting great acquaintance was more than excusable in the view of defeating her.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="2"/>
<context>
"I do not suppose the situation my friend Mrs Rooke is in at present, will furnish much either to interest or edify me.  She is only nursing Mrs Wallis of Marlborough Buildings; a mere pretty, silly, expensive, fashionable woman, I <head>believe</head>; and of course will have nothing to report but of lace and finery.  I mean to make my profit of Mrs Wallis, however. She has plenty of money, and I intend she shall buy all the high-priced things I have in hand now."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="2"/>
<context>
of being restored to Kellynch, calling it her home again, her home for ever, was a charm which she could not immediately resist. Lady Russell said not another word, willing to leave the matter to its own operation; and <head>believing</head> that, could Mr Elliot at that moment with propriety have spoken for himself!- she believed, in short, what Anne did not believe.  The same image of Mr Elliot speaking for himself brought Anne to composure again.  The charm of Kellynch and of "Lady Elliot" all faded away.  She never could accept him. And it was not only that her feelings were still adverse to any man save one; her judgement, on a serious consideration of the possibilities
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="2"/>
<context>
You must be a great deal too happy to care for Uppercross, which, as you well know, affords little to write about.  We have had a very dull Christmas; Mr and Mrs Musgrove have not had one dinner party all the holidays.  I do not reckon the Hayters as anybody. The holidays, however, are over at last:  I <head>believe</head> no children ever had such long ones.  I am sure I had not.  The house was cleared yesterday, except of the little Harvilles; but you will be surprised to hear they have never gone home. Mrs Harville must be an odd mother to part with them so long.  I do not understand it.  They are
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="2"/>
<context>
as a very amiable, sweet-tempered girl, and not deficient in understanding, but Benwick is something more.  He is a clever man, a reading man; and I confess, that I do consider his attaching himself to her with some surprise.  Had it been the effect of gratitude, had he learnt to love her, because he <head>believed</head> her to be preferring him, it would have been another thing.  But I have no reason to suppose it so. It seems, on the contrary, to have been a perfectly spontaneous, untaught feeling on his side, and this surprises me.  A man like him, in his situation! with a heart pierced, wounded, almost broken!
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="2"/>
<context>
very extraordinary; flattering, but painful.  There was much to regret. How she might have felt had there been no Captain Wentworth in the case, was not worth enquiry; for there was a Captain Wentworth; and be the conclusion of the present suspense good or bad, her affection would be his for ever.  Their union, she <head>believed</head>, could not divide her more from other men, than their final separation. Prettier musings of high-wrought love and eternal constancy, could never have passed along the streets of Bath, than Anne
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="2"/>
<context>
shipwrecked as mine has been.  You are safe in all worldly matters, and safe in his character.  He will not be led astray; he will not be misled by others to his ruin." "No," said Anne, "I can readily <head>believe</head> all that of my cousin. He seems to have a calm decided temper, not at all open to dangerous impressions.  I consider him with great respect. I have no reason, from any thing that has fallen within my observation, to do otherwise.  But I have not known him long; and he is not a man,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the more inclined to wonder at the composure of her friend's usual state of mind.There was one circumstance in the history of her grievances of particular irritation.  She had good reason to <head>believe</head> that some property of her husband in the West Indies, which had been for many years under a sort of sequestration for the payment of its own incumbrances, might be recoverable by proper measures; and this property, though not large, would be enough to make
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="2"/>
<context>
from all those ambitious feelings which have led to so much misconduct and misery, both in young and old.  I hope you think Louisa perfectly recovered now?"He answered rather hesitatingly, "Yes, I <head>believe</head> I do; very much recovered; but she is altered; there is no running or jumping about, no laughing or dancing; it is quite different.  If one happens only to shut the door a little hard, she starts and wriggles like a young dab-chick in the water; and Benwick sits at her elbow, reading verses, or whispering to her,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="2"/>
<context>
still more positively that it was Mr Elliot, calling again upon Anne to come and look for herself, but Anne did not mean to stir, and tried to be cool and unconcerned.  Her distress returned, however, on perceiving smiles and intelligent glances pass between two or three of the lady visitors, as if they <head>believed</head> themselves quite in the secret.  It was evident that the report concerning her had spread, and a short pause succeeded, which seemed to ensure that it would now spread farther.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="2"/>
<context>
And when I think of Benwick, my tongue is tied." Their attention was called towards the others. Mrs Croft was taking leave. "Here, Frederick, you and I part company, I <head>believe</head>,” said she. "I am going home, and you have an engagement with your friend. To-night we may have the pleasure of all meeting again at your party," (turning to Anne.)  "We had your sister's card yesterday, and I understood Frederick had a card too, though I did not see it;
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="2"/>
<context>
buried, lost in those earlier feelings which I had been smarting under year after year.  I could think of you only as one who had yielded, who had given me up, who had been influenced by any one rather than by me. I saw you with the very person who had guided you in that year of misery. I had no reason to <head>believe</head> her of less authority now.  The force of habit was to be added." "I should have thought," said Anne, "that my manner to yourself might have spared you much or all of this."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="2"/>
<context>
in admiring a fine display of greenhouse plants, that she said-- "I have been thinking over the past, and trying impartially to judge of the right and wrong, I mean with regard to myself; and I must <head>believe</head> that I was right, much as I suffered from it, that I was perfectly right in being guided by the friend whom you will love better than you do now.  To me, she was in the place of a parent.  Do not mistake me, however.  I am not saying that she did not err in her advice.  It was, perhaps, one of those cases
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The Indo-Europeans in antiquity included the Hindus of India, the Medes and Persians dwelling on the plateau of Iran, the Greeks and Italians, and most of the inhabitants of central and western Europe. All these peoples spoke related languages which are <head>believed</head> to be offshoots from one common tongue. Likeness in language does not imply that all Indo-Europeans were closely related in blood. Men often adopt a foreign tongue and pass it on to their children.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Agriculture was the chief occupation of the Roman people. "When our forefathers," said an ancient writer, "would praise a worthy man, they praised him as a good farmer and a good landlord; and they <head>believed</head> that an praise could go no further." [10] Roman farmers raised large crops of grain--the staple product of ancient Italy. Cattle-breeding, also, must have been an important pursuit, since in early times prices were estimated in oxen and sheep.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The First Punic War was a contest for Sicily. The Carthaginians aimed to establish their rule over that island, which from its situation seems to belong almost as much to Africa as to Italy. But Rome, having become supreme in Italy, also cast envious eyes on Sicily. She <head>believed</head>, too, that the Carthaginians, if they should conquer Sicily, would sooner or later invade southern Italy. The fear for her possessions, as well as the desire to gain new ones, led Rome to fling down the gage of battle.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The steady advance of the Carthaginian arms in Spain caused much uneasiness in Rome and at length led that city to declare war. Carthage herself was not unwilling for a second trial of strength. Her leading general, Hannibal, who had been winning renown in Spain, <head>believed</head> that the Carthaginians were now in a position to wage an aggressive war against their mighty rival. And so the two great Mediterranean powers, each confident of success, renewed the struggle for supremacy.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="2"/>
<context>
and prudent statesman. He proposed to bestow the right of voting in the Roman assemblies upon the inhabitants of the Latin colonies. [20] He thought, also, that the Italian allies should be allowed to intermarry with Romans and hold property under the protection of the Roman law. No doubt Gaius <head>believed</head> that the time might come when all the Italian peoples would be citizens of Rome. This time did come, thirty years later, but only after a terrible war that nearly ruined Rome.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The effort by Gaius to extend Roman citizenship cost the reformer all his hard-won popularity. It aroused the jealousy of the selfish city mob, which <head>believed</head> that the entrance of so many new citizens would mean the loss of its privileges. There would not be so many free shows and so much cheap grain. So the people rejected the measure and, turning from their former favorite, failed to reëlect him to the tribunate. When Gaius was no longer protected by the sanctity of the tribune's office, [21] he fell an
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="2"/>
<context>
balance Rome in the western half. Again, Constantinople, far more than Rome, was the military center of the empire. Rome lay too far from the vulnerable frontiers; Constantinople occupied a position about equidistant from the Germans on the lower Danube and the Persians on the Euphrates. Finally, Constantine <head>believed</head> that Christianity, which he wished to become the prevailing religion, would encounter less opposition and criticism in his new city than at Rome, with its pagan atmosphere and traditions. Constantinople was to be not simply a new seat of government but also distinctively a Christian capital. Such it remained for more than eleven
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="2"/>
<context>
made Octavian supreme in the Roman world. If we except the abandonment of Trajan's conquests beyond the Danube and the Euphrates, [9] no part of the huge empire had as yet succumbed to its enemies. The subject peoples, during these four centuries, had not tried to overthrow the empire or to withdraw from its protection. The Roman state, men <head>believed</head>, would endure forever. Yet the times were drawing nigh when the old order of things was to be broken up; when barbarian invaders were to seize the fairest provinces as their own; and when new kingdoms, ruled by men of Germanic speech, were to arise in lands that once obeyed Rome.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Christianity rose among the Jews, for Jesus was a Jew and his disciples were Jews. At the time of the death of Jesus [17] his immediate followers numbered scarcely a Christianity hundred persons. The catastrophe of the crucifixion struck them with sorrow and dismay. When, however, the disciples came to <head>believe</head> in the resurrection of their master, a wonderful impetus was given to the growth of the new religion. They now asserted that Jesus was the true Messiah, or Christ, who by rising from the dead had sealed the truth of his teachings. For several years after the crucifixion, the disciples remained at Jerusalem, preaching and making
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="2"/>
<context>
By this time the Church had become a great and powerful organization, with fixed laws, with a graded system of officers, and with councils attended by clergy from all parts of the Roman world. To this organization the word Catholic, that is, "universal," came to be applied. Membership in the Catholic Church, secured only by baptism, was <head>believed</head> to be essential to salvation. As St. Cyprian, bishop of Carthage, had said, "He can no longer have God for his Father who has not the Church for his Mother."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="2"/>
<context>
into Arabic and enriched the work with illuminated maps. Arab scholars compiled encyclopedias describing foreign countries and peoples, constructed celestial spheres, and measured closely the arc of the meridian in order to calculate the size of the earth. There is some reason to <head>believe</head> that the mariner's compass was first introduced into Europe by the Arabs. The geographical knowledge of Christian peoples during the Middle Ages owed much, indeed, to their Moslem forerunners.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="2"/>
<context>
A form of trial which especially appealed to the warlike nobles was the judicial duel. [6] The accuser and the accused fought with each other; and the conqueror won the case. God, it was <head>believed</head>, would give victory to the innocent party, because he had right on his side. When one of the adversaries could not fight, he secured a champion to take his place. Though the judicial duel finally went out of use in the law courts, it still continued to be employed privately, as a means of settling disputes
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The sacrament of the Holy Eucharist, generally known as the Mass, formed the central feature of worship. It was more than a common meal in commemoration of the Last Supper of Christ with the Apostles. It was a solemn ceremony, by which the Christian <head>believed</head> himself to receive the body and blood of Christ, under the form of bread and wine. [3] The right of the priest to withhold the Eucharist from any person, for good cause, gave the Church great power, because the failure to partake of this sacrament imperiled one's chances of future salvation. It was also
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="2"/>
<context>
activities, differences in dress, and the obligation of celibacy. [16] Being unmarried, the clergy had no family cares; being free from the necessity of earning their own living, they could devote all their time and energy to the service of the Church. The sacrament of Ordination, which was <head>believed</head> to endow the clergy with divine power, also helped to strengthen their influence. They appeared as a distinct order, in whose charge was the care of souls and in whose hands were the keys of heaven.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="2"/>
<context>
lost faith in the movement. But after two centuries the old crusading enthusiasm died out, the old ideal of the crusade as "the way of God" lost its spell. Men had begun to think less of winning future salvation by visits to distant shrines and to think more of their present duties to the world about them. They came to <head>believe</head> that Jerusalem could best be won as Christ and the Apostles had won it--"by love, by prayers, and by the shedding of tears."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="2"/>
<context>
As an old chronicler wrote, "It was as if the whole world had thrown off the rags of its ancient time, and had arrayed itself in the white robes of the churches." The term Gothic was applied contemptuously to this architectural style by writers of the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, who regarded everything non-classical as barbarous. They <head>believed</head> it to be an invention of the barbarian Goths, and so they called it Gothic. The name has stuck, as bad names have a habit of doing, but nowadays every one recognizes the greatness of this medieval art. The most beautiful buildings of the Middle Ages are of Gothic architecture.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The study of chemistry also engaged the attention of medieval investigators. It was, however, much mixed up with alchemy, a false science which the Middle Ages had received from the Greeks, and they, in turn, from the Egyptians. The alchemists <head>believed</head> that minerals possessed a real life of their own and that they were continually developing in the ground toward the state of gold, the perfect metal. It was necessary, therefore, to discover the "philosopher's stone," which would turn all metals into gold. The alchemists never found it, but they learned a good
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Astronomy in the Middle Ages was the most advanced of any natural science, though the telescope and the Copernican theory [26] were as yet in the future. Astronomy, the wise mother, had a foolish daughter, astrology, the origin of which can be traced back to Babylonia. [27] Medieval students no longer regarded the stars as divine, but they <head>believed</head> that the natural world and the life of men were controlled by celestial influences. Hence astrologers professed to predict the fate of a person from the position of the planets at the time of his birth. Astrological rules were also drawn from the signs of the zodiac. A child born under the sign of the Lion will
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The books printed in the fifteenth century go by the name of _incunabula_. [7] Of the seven or eight million volumes which appeared before 1500 A.D., about thirty thousand are <head>believed</head> to be still in existence. Many of these earliest books were printed in heavy, "black letter" type, an imitation of the characters used in monkish manuscripts. It is still retained for most books printed in Germany. The clearer and neater "Roman" characters, resembling the letters employed for ancient Roman inscriptions, came into
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="2"/>
<context>
teaching, stands for a reaction against humanistic education. He proposed that the vernacular tongues, as well as the classics, should be made subjects of study. For this purpose he prepared a reading book, which was translated into a dozen European languages, and even into Arabic, Persian, and Turkish. Comenius also <head>believed</head> that the curriculum should include the study of geography, world history, and government, and the practice of the manual arts. He was one of the first to advocate the teaching of science. Perhaps his most notable idea was that of a national system of education, reaching from primary grades to the university. "Not only," he writes,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The demarcation line had a good deal to do in bringing about the first voyage around the globe. So far no one had yet realized the dream of Columbus to reach the lands of spice and silk by sailing westward. Ferdinand Magellan, formerly one of Albuquerque's lieutenants but now in the service of Spain, <head>believed</head> that the Spice Islands lay within the Spanish sphere of influence and that an all-Spanish route, leading to them through some strait at the southern end of South America, could be discovered.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Tudor king, Henry VII. [31] In 1497 A.D. Cabot sailed from Bristol across the northern Atlantic and made land somewhere between Labrador and Nova Scotia. The following year he seems to have undertaken a second voyage and to have explored the coast of North America nearly as far as Florida. Cabot, like Columbus, <head>believed</head> he had reached Cathay and the dominions of the Great Khan. Because Cabot found neither gold nor opportunities for profitable trade, his expeditions were considered a failure, and for a long time the English took no further interest in exploring the New World.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The reformers agreed in substituting for the authority of popes and church councils the authority of the Bible. They went back fifteen hundred years to the time of the Apostles and tried to restore what they <head>believed</head> to be Apostolic Christianity. Hence they rejected such doctrines and practices as were supposed to have developed during the Middle Ages. The Reformation also abolished the monastic system and priestly celibacy. The sharp distinction between clergy and laity disappeared, for priests married,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The man who did most to reveal the prehistoric civilization of Greece was a wealthy German merchant named Heinrich Schliemann. An enthusiastic lover of Homer, he <head>believed</head> that the stories of the Trojan War related in the _Iliad_ were not idle fancies, but real facts. In 1870 A.D. he started to test his beliefs by excavations at a hill called Hissarlik, on the northwestern coast of Asia Minor. Here tradition had always fixed the site of ancient Troy. Schliemann's discoveries and those of later explorers
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="2"/>
<context>
violence against the opposing ship, in order to disable or sink it. A sea fight became a series of maneuvers; and victory depended as much on the skill of the rowers and steersmen as on the bravery of the soldiers. The Persians at Salamis had many more ships than the Greeks, but Themistocles rightly <head>believed</head> that in the narrow strait their numbers would be a real disadvantage to them. Such proved to be the case. The Persians fought well, but their vessels, crowded together, could not navigate properly and even wrecked one another by collision. After an all-day contest what remained of their fleet withdrew from the strait.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The system of philosophy called Epicureanism was founded by a Greek named Epicurus. He taught in Athens during the earlier part of the third century B.C. Epicurus <head>believed</head> that pleasure is the sole good, pain, the sole evil. He meant by pleasure not so much the passing enjoyments of the hour as the permanent happiness of a lifetime. In order to be happy men should not trouble themselves with useless luxuries, but should lead the "simple life." They must be virtuous, for virtue will bring more real satisfaction
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The coronation of Charlemagne was one of the most important events in medieval history. It might be thought a small matter that he should take the imperial title, when he already exercised imperial sway throughout western Europe. But Charlemagne's contemporaries <head>believed</head> that the old Roman Empire had now been revived, and a German king now sat on the throne once occupied by Augustus and Constantine. Henceforth there was established in the West a line of Roman emperors which lasted until the opening of the nineteenth century.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="2"/>
<context>
many years, but finally came to the conclusion that he could never subdue the Netherlands or end the piracy and smuggling in Spanish America without first conquering England. The execution of Mary Stuart removed his last doubts, for Mary had left him her claims to the English throne. He at once made ready to invade England. Philip seems to have <head>believed</head> that as soon as a Spanish army landed in the island, the Roman Catholics would rally to his cause. But the Spanish king never had a chance to verify his belief; the decisive battle took place on the sea.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Cromwell represented the university of Cambridge in the Long Parliament and displayed there great audacity in opposing the government. An unfriendly critic at this time describes "his countenance swollen and reddish, his voice sharp and untuneable, and his eloquence full of fervor." Though a zealous Puritan, who <head>believed</head> himself in all sincerity to be the chosen agent of the Lord, Cromwell was not an ascetic. He hunted, hawked, played bowls, and other games, had an ear for music, and valued art and learning. In public life he showed himself a statesman of much insight and a military genius.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="2"/>
<context>
paralyzing blows at the scattered bands that constituted the American army. "Nothing but the supineness or folly of the enemy could have saved us," solemnly averred Washington in 1780. Still it is fair to say that this apparent supineness was not all due to the British generals. The ministers behind them <head>believed</head> that a large part of the colonists were loyal and that compromise would be promoted by inaction rather than by a war vigorously prosecuted. Victory by masterly inactivity was obviously better than conquest, and the slighter the wounds the quicker the healing. Later in the conflict when the seasoned forces of France were
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The method of selecting federal officers and members of Congress also produced an acrimonious debate which revealed how deep-seated was the distrust of the capacity of the people to govern themselves. Few there were who <head>believed</head> that no branch of the government should be elected directly by the voters; still fewer were there, however, who desired to see all branches so chosen. One or two even expressed a desire for a monarchy. The dangers of democracy were stressed by Gerry of Massachusetts: "All the evils we experience
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The mobs of great cities, he said, are sores on the body politic; artisans are usually the dangerous element that make revolutions; workshops should be kept in Europe and with them the artisans with their insidious morals and manners. The only substantial foundation for a republic, Jefferson <head>believed</head> to be agriculture. The spirit of independence could be kept alive only by free farmers, owning the land they tilled and looking to the sun in heaven and the labor of their hands for their sustenance. Trusting as he did in the innate goodness of human nature when nourished on a free soil, Jefferson advocated those
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="2"/>
<context>
American people, as well as the constitutions of the states and the nation, he came to the conclusion that democracy with all its faults was both inevitable and successful. Slavery he thought was a painful contrast to the other features of American life, and he foresaw what proved to be the irrepressible conflict over it. He <head>believed</head> that through blundering the people were destined to learn the highest of all arts, self-government on a grand scale. The absence of a leisure class, devoted to no calling or profession, merely enjoying the refinements of life and adding to its graces--the flaw in American culture that gave
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The following year the interest of the whole country was drawn to a series of debates held in Illinois by Lincoln and Douglas, both candidates for the United States Senate. In the course of his campaign Lincoln had uttered his trenchant saying that "a house divided against itself cannot stand. I <head>believe</head> this government cannot endure permanently half slave and half free." At the same time he had accused Douglas, Buchanan, and the Supreme Court of acting in concert to make slavery national. This daring statement arrested the attention of Douglas, who was making his campaign on the doctrine of
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="2"/>
<context>
had declared that Congress, the superior power, could not do it under the Constitution? To this baffling question Douglas lamely replied that the inhabitants of a territory, by "unfriendly legislation," might make property in slaves insecure and thus destroy the institution. This answer to Lincoln's query alienated many Southern Democrats who <head>believed</head> that the Dred Scott decision settled the question of slavery in the territories for all time. Douglas won the election to the Senate; but Lincoln, lifted into national fame by the debates, beat him in the campaign for President two years later.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="1"/>
<context>
the instrument itself; even if it is a compact among all the states the consent of all must be necessary to its dissolution; therefore no state can lawfully get out of the union and acts of violence against the United States are insurrectionary or revolutionary. This was the system which he <head>believed</head> himself bound to defend by his oath of office "registered in heaven.”All this reasoning Southern statesmen utterly rejected. In their opinion the thirteen original states won their independence as separate and
</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
