<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="1"/>
<context>
New England, fish, flour, rum, furs, shoes,and small articles of manufacture. The variety of products was in fact astounding. A sarcastic writer, while sneering at the <head>idea</head> of an American union, once remarked of colonial trade: "What sort of dish will you make? New England will throw in fish and onions. The middle states, flax-seed and flour. Maryland and Virginia will add tobacco.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="1"/>
<context>
character was declared to be compulsory, and provision was made for public schools where those not taught at home could receive instruction in reading and writing.Outside of New England the <head>idea</head> of compulsory education was not regarded with the same favor; but the whole land was nevertheless dotted with little schools kept by "dames, itinerant teachers, or local parsons."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Coincident with the drift toward administration through royal governors was the second and opposite tendency, namely, a steady growth in the practice of self-government.The voters of England had long been accustomed to share in taxation and law-making through representatives in Parliament, and the <head>idea</head> was early introduced in America. Virginia was only twelve years old (1619) when its first representative assembly appeared. As the towns of Massachusetts multiplied and.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="1"/>
<context>
As the towns of Massachusetts multiplied and it became impossible for all the members of the corporation to meet at one place, the representative <head>idea</head> was adopted, in 1633. The river towns of Connecticut formed a representative system under their "Fundamental Orders" of 1639, and the entire colony was given a royal charter in 1662. 
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="1"/>
<context>
British measures offered by Massachusetts and promised the united support of all sections. It prepared an address to King George and another to the people of England, disavowing the <head>idea</head> of independence but firmly attacking the policies pursued by the British government.The Congress was not content, however, with professions of faith and with petitions.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Among the members of Parliament who thundered against the government were the first statesmen and orators of the land. William Pitt, Earl of Chatham, though he deplored the <head>idea</head> of American independence, denounced the government as the aggressor and rejoiced in American resistance. Edmund Burke leveled his heavy batteries against every measure of coercion.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Indian War and was staggering under a heavy burden of debt and taxes. The war had been fought partly in defense of the American colonies and nothing seemed more reasonable to English statesmen than the <head>idea</head> that the colonies should bear part of the cost of their own defense. At this juncture there came into prominence, in royal councils, two men bent on taxing America and controlling her trade.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="1"/>
<context>
In the midst of his doubts came the news that Napoleon might withdraw from the bargain. Thoroughly alarmed by that, Jefferson pressed the Senate for a ratification of the treaty. He still clung to his original <head>idea</head> that the Constitution did not warrant the purchase; but he lamely concluded: "If our friends shall think differently, I shall certainly acquiesce with satisfaction; confident.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The Republicans seemed far awayfrom the days of "strict construction." And Jefferson still lived! Even more effective in fashioning the national <head>idea</head> was Monroe's enunciation of the famous doctrine that bears his name. The occasion was another European crisis. During the Napoleonic upheaval and the years of dissolution that ensued.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="1"/>
<context>
No differences of opinion as to his political views have ever led even his warmest opponents to deny his superb abilities or his sincere devotion to the national <head>idea</head>. All will likewise agree that for talents, native and acquired, he was an ornament to the humble democracy that brought him forth. His whole career was American.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Indianians drafted a constitution and inaugurated their government at Corydon. "The majority of the members of the convention," we are told by a local historian, "were frontier farmers who had a general <head>idea</head> of what they wanted and had sense enough to let their more erudite colleagues put it into shape."Two years later, the pioneers of Illinois, also settled upward from the Ohio, like Indiana, elected their delegates to draft a constitution.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="1"/>
<context>
A people so independent as the Westerners and so attached to local self-government gave the conservative East many a rude shock, setting gentlemen in powdered wigs and knee breeches agog with the <head>idea</head> that terrible things might happen in the Mississippi Valley. Not without good grounds did Washington fear that "a touch of a feather would turn" the Western settlers away from the seaboard to the Spaniards.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="1"/>
<context>
In Virginia, Jefferson himself had first believed in property qualifications and had feared with genuine alarm the "mobs of the great cities." It was near the end of the eighteenth century before he accepted the <head>idea</head> of manhood suffrage. Even then he was unable to convince the constitution-makers of his own state. "It is not an idle chimera of the brain," urged one of them, "that the possession of land furnishes the strongest evidence of permanent.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="1"/>
<context>
notably New York and Pennsylvania. Closely connected with it was the practice of fixing short terms for officers and making frequent changes in personnel. "Long continuance in office," explained a champion of this <head>idea</head> in Pennsylvania in 1837, "unfits a man for the discharge of its duties, by rendering him arbitrary and aristocratic, and tends to beget, first life office, and then hereditary office, which leads to the destruction of free government.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="1"/>
<context>
In 1824, Vermont, New York, Delaware, South Carolina, Georgia, and Louisiana, though some had experimented with popular election, still left the choice of electors with the legislature. Eight years later South Carolina alone held to the old practice. Popular election had become the final word.The fanciful <head>idea</head> of an electoral college of "good and wise men,"selected without passion or partisanship by state legislatures acting as deliberative bodies, was exploded for all time; the election of the nation's chief magistrate was committed to the tempestuous methods of democracy.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Van Buren, at heart opposed to slavery extension, refused to press the issue of annexation. Tyler, a pro-slavery Democrat from Virginia, by a strange fling of fortune carried into office as a nominal Whig, kept his mind firmly fixed on the <head>idea</head> of reëlection and let the troublesome matter rest until the end of his administration was in sight. He then listened with favor to the voice of the South. Calhoun stated what seemed to be a convincing argument
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Still no extensive effort was made to solve by law the economic problems of the bondmen. Radical abolitionists had advocated that the slaves whenemancipated should be given outright the fields of their former masters; but Congress steadily rejected the very <head>idea</head> of confiscation. The necessity of immediate assistance it recognized by creating in 1865 the Freedmen's Bureau to take care of refugees. It authorized the issue of food and clothing to the destitute
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The trustees, in turn, issued certificates representing the share to which each participant was entitled; and took over the management of the entire business. Such was the nature of the "trust," which was to play such an unique rôle in the progress of America. The <head>idea</head> of combination was applied in time to iron and steel, copper, lead, sugar, cordage, coal, and other commodities, until in each field there loomed a giant trust or corporation, controlling, if not most of the output
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="1"/>
<context>
A decade before the Civil War the importance of rail connection between the East and the Pacific Coast had been recognized. Pressure had already been brought to bear on Congress to authorize the construction of a line and to grant land and money in its aid. Both the Democrats and Republicans approved the <head>idea</head>, but it was involved in the slavery controversy. Indeed it was submerged in it.Southern statesmen wanted connections between the Gulf and the Pacific through Texas, while Northerners stood out for a central route
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="1"/>
<context>
It has now become a fashion, sanctioned by wide usage and by eminent historians, to speak of America, triumphant over Spain and possessed of new colonies, as entering the twentieth century in the rôle of "a world power," for the first time. Perhaps at this late day, it is useless to protest against the currency of the <head>idea</head>. Nevertheless, the truth is that from the fateful moment in March, 1775, when Edmund Burke unfolded to his colleagues in the British Parliament the resources of an invincible America, down to the settlement at Versailles in 1919 closing the drama of the World War
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The most important foreign question confronting President Roosevelt on the day of his inauguration, that of the Panama Canal, was a heritage from his predecessor. The <head>idea</head> of a water route across the isthmus, long a dream of navigators, had become a living issue after the historic voyage of the battleship _Oregon_ around South America during the Spanish War. But before the United States could act it had to undo the Clayton-Bulwer treaty
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="1"/>
<context>
let us destroy therefore the tariff and the trusts"--such was the battle cry which had been takenup by Bryan and his followers.President Roosevelt countered vigorously. He rejected the <head>idea</head> that the trusts were the product of the tariff or of governmental action of any kind. He insisted that they were the outcome of "natural economic forces"
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="1"/>
<context>
it was looked upon as the "citadel of conservatism." The prescription in this case was likewise "more democracy"--direct election of Senators by popular vote. This reform was not a new <head>idea</head>. It had been proposed in Congress as early as 1826. President Johnson, an ardent advocate, made it the subject of a special message in 1868 Not long afterward it appeared in Congress. At last in 1893
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Commissioners were often lacking in the technical ability required to manage such difficult matters as fire and police protection, public health, public works, and public utilities. Some one then proposed to carry over into city government an <head>idea</head> from the business world. In that sphere the stockholders of each corporation elect the directors and the directors, in turn, choose a business manager to conduct the affairs of the company
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="1"/>
<context>
A third group of reformers were satisfied with nothing short of municipal ownership. They proposed to drive private companies entirely out of the field and vest the ownership and management of municipal plants in the city itself. This <head>idea</head> was extensively applied to electric light and water works plants, but to street railways in only a few cities, including San Francisco and Seattle. In New York the subways are owned by the city but leased for operation
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The immediate answer was the enactment of a tenement house law prescribing in great detail the size of the rooms, the air space, the light and the sanitary arrangement for all new buildings. An immense improvement followed and the <head>idea</head> was quickly taken up in other states having large industrial centers. In 1920 New York made a further invasion of the rights of landlords by assuring to the public "reasonable rents" for flats and apartments
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The discussion revealed a wide range of duties assigned to managers, including questions of wages, hours, sanitation, rest rooms, recreational facilities, and welfare work of every kind designed to make the conditions in mills and factories safer and more humane. Thus it was evident that hundreds of employers had abandoned the old <head>idea</head> that they were dealing merely with individual employees and that their obligations ended with the payment of any wages they saw fit to fix. In short, they were seeking to develop a spirit of coöperation to take the place of competition and enmity
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="1"/>
<context>
For a time this movement attracted wide interest, but it had little vitality. Nearly all the colonies failed. Selfishness and indolence usually disrupted the best of them.In the course of time this "Utopian" <head>idea</head> was abandoned, and another set of socialist doctrines, claiming to be more "scientific," appeared instead. The new school of socialists, adopting the principles of a German writer and agitator
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Indeed a material reduction was resolutely opposed in many quarters. People of certain nationalities already in the United States objected to every barrier that shut out their own kinsmen. Some Americans of the old stock still held to the <head>idea</head> that the United States should continue to be an asylum for "the oppressed of the earth." Many employers looked upon an increased labor supply as the means of escaping what they called "the domination of trade unions
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Some other New England towns, refusing to profit by the experience of their Plymouth neighbor, also made excursions into common ownership and labor, only to abandon the <head>idea</head> and go in for individual ownership of the land. "By degrees it was seen that even the Lord's people could not carry the complicated communist legislation into perfect and wholesome practice
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="1"/>
<context>
On rolls of birch bark or the skins of animals they wrote messages, hunting stories, and songs, and even preserved tribal annals extending over a century.A new stage in the development of writing was reached when the picture represented, not an actual object or an <head>idea</head>, but a sound of the human voice. This difficult but all-important step appears to have been taken through the use of the rebus, that is, writing words by pictures of objects which stand for sounds
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Hera, the wife of Zeus, represented the female principle in nature. Hence she presided over the life of women and especially over the sacred rites of marriage. Athena, who sprang full-grown from the forehead of Zeus, embodied the <head>idea</head> of wisdom and all womanly virtues. Aphrodite, who arose from the foam of the sea, was the goddess of love and beauty. Demeter, the great earth- mother, watched over seed-time and harvest. Each deity thus had a kingdom and a function of its own
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="1"/>
<context>
It was clear proof that the Persian power, however imposing on the outside, could offer no effective resistance to an attack by a strong force of disciplined Greek soldiers. Henceforth the Greeks never abandoned the <head>idea</head> of an invasion of Persia.The gigantic task fell, however, to Alexander, as the champion of Hellas against the "barbarians.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The Romans always regarded the _manes_ as members of the household to which they had belonged on earth. The living and the dead were thus bound together by the closest ties. The <head>idea</head> of the family triumphed even over the grave.The ancient Roman house had only one large room, the _atrium_, where all members of the family lived together
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The end of all things arrived. This was the catastrophe which had been predicted of old--the "Twilight of the Gods.Besides the conception of Hel, the Northmen also framed the <head>idea</head> of Valhalla, [6] the abode to which Odin received the souls of those who had died, not ingloriously in their beds, but on the field of battle. A troop of divine maidens, the Valkyries
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Representatives of the counties had been employed by the Norman kings to act as assessors in levying taxes. As we have just learned, the "juries" of Henry II also consisted of such representatives. The English people, in fact, were quite familiar with the <head>idea</head> of representation long before it was applied on a larger scale to Parliament."MODEL PARLIAMENT" OF EDWARD I, 1295 A.D.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="1"/>
<context>
It was thought wrong for anyone to purchase goods outside of the regular market ("forestalling") or to purchase them in larger quantities than necessary ("engrossing"). A man ought not to charge for a thing more than it was worth, or to buy a thing cheap and sell it dear. The <head>idea</head> prevailed that goods should be sold at their "just price" which was not determined by supply and demand but by an estimate of the cost of the materials and the labor that went into their manufacture
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="1"/>
<context>
omenius also believed that the curriculum should include the study of geography, world history, and government, and the practice of the manual arts. He was one of the first to advocate the teaching of science. Perhaps his most notable <head>idea</head> was that of a national system of education, reaching from primary grades to the university. "Not only," he writes,"are the children of the rich and noble to be drawn to school, but all alike, rich and poor, boys and girls, in great towns and small, down to the country villages.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="1"/>
<context>
In the Middle Ages students had mostly been satisfied to accept what Aristotle and other philosophers had said, without trying to prove their statements. [20] Kepler, for instance, was the first to disprove the Aristotelian <head>idea</head> that, as all perfect motion is circular, therefore the heavenly bodies must move in circular orbits. Similarly, the world had to wait many centuries before Harvey showed Aristotle's error in supposing that the blood arose in the liver, went thence to the heart.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Columbus knew the Mediterranean by heart; he once went to the Guinea coast; and he may have visited Iceland. He settled at Lisbon as a map-maker and married a daughter of one of Prince Henry's sea-captains. As Columbus pored over his maps and charts and talked with seamen about their voyages, the <head>idea</head> came to him that much of the world remained undiscovered and that the distant East could be reached by a shorter route than that which led around Africa.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The Spaniards, during the earlier part of the sixteenth century, heard much of a fabled king whom they called El Dorado. [27] This king, it was said, used to smear himself with gold dust at an annual religious ceremony. In time the <head>idea</head> arose that somewhere in South America existed a fabled country marvelously rich in precious metals and gems. These stories stirred the imagination of the Spaniards, who fitted out many expeditions to find the gilded man and his gilded realm.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="1"/>
<context>
During the seventeenth century they took a prominent part in European affairs. The republic which they founded ought to be of special interest to Americans, for many features of our national government are Dutch in origin. To Holland we owe the <head>idea</head> of a declaration of independence, of a written constitution, of religious toleration, and of a comprehensive school system supported by taxation. In these and other matters the Dutch were pioneers of modern democracy.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Providence, they argued, had never sanctioned the Papacy, but Providence had really ordained the State and had placed over it a king whom it was a religious duty to obey. Even those who were not reformers distorted the Christian <head>idea</head> that government has a divine basis to represent kings as God's vicegerents upon earth, as in fact earthly deities.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Elizabeth did not quite equal her father in personal contentment. Thirteen years had seen her mistress of Kellynch Hall, presiding and directing with a self-possession and decision which could never have given the <head>idea</head> of her being younger than she was.  For thirteen years had she been doing the honours, and laying down the domestic law at home, and leading the way to the chaise and four, and walking immediately after Lady Russell out of all the drawing-rooms and dining-rooms in the country.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Sir Walter could not have borne the degradation of being known to design letting his house.  Mr Shepherd had once mentioned the word "advertise," but never dared approach it again.  Sir Walter spurned the <head>idea</head> of its being offered in any manner; forbad the slightest hint being dropped of his having such an intention; and it was only on the supposition of his being spontaneously solicited by some most unexceptionable applicant, on his own terms, and as a great favour, that he would let it at all.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="1"/>
<context>
I am not particularly disposed to favour a tenant. The park would be open to him of course, and few navy officers, or men of any other description, can have had such a range; but what restrictions I might impose on the use of the pleasure-grounds, is another thing.  I am not fond of the <head>idea</head> of my shrubberies being always approachable; and I should recommend Miss Elliot to be on her guard with respect to her flower garden.  I am very little disposed to grant a tenant of Kellynch Hall any extraordinary favour, I assure you, be he sailor or soldier.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="1"/>
<context>
With all these circumstances, recollections and feelings, she could not hear that Captain Wentworth's sister was likely to live at Kellynch without a revival of former pain; and many a stroll, and many a sigh, were necessary to dispel the agitation of the <head>idea</head>. She often told herself it was folly, before she could harden her nerves sufficiently to feel the continual discussion of the Crofts and their business no evil.  She was assisted, however, by that perfect indifference and apparent unconsciousness, among the only three of her own friends in the secret of the past, which seemed almost to deny any recollection of it
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="1"/>
<context>
With a great deal of quiet observation, and a knowledge, which she often wished less, of her father's character, she was sensible that results the most serious to his family from the intimacy were more than possible.  She did not imagine that her father had at present an <head>idea</head> of the kind.  Mrs Clay had freckles, and a projecting tooth, and a clumsy wrist, which he was continually making severe remarks upon, in her absence; but she was young, and certainly altogether well-looking, and possessed, in an acute mind and assiduous pleasing manners
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Anne had not wanted this visit to Uppercross, to learn that a removal from one set of people to another, though at a distance of only three miles, will often include a total change of conversation, opinion, and <head>idea</head>. She had never been staying there before, without being struck by it, or without wishing that other Elliots could have her advantage in seeing how unknown, or unconsidered there, were the affairs which at Kellynch Hall were treated as of such general publicity and pervading interest
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="1"/>
<context>
They were of sobering tendency;they allayed agitation; they composed, and consequently must make her happier.Frederick Wentworth had used such words, or something like them, but without an <head>idea</head> that they would be carried round to her. He had thought her wretchedly altered, and in the first moment of appeal,had spoken as he felt
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Once, too, he spoke to her.  She had left the instrument on the dancing being over, and he had sat down to try to make out an air which he wished to give the Miss Musgroves an <head>idea</head> of. Unintentionally she returned to that part of the room; he saw her, and, instantly rising, said, with studied politeness--"I beg your pardon, madam, this is your seat;"
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="1"/>
<context>
What! would I be turned back from doing a thing that I had determined to do, and that I knew to be right,by the airs and interference of such a person, or of any person I may say? No, I have no <head>idea</head> of being so easily persuaded.  When I have made up my mind, I have made it; and Henrietta seemed entirely to have made up hers to call at Winthrop to-day; and yet, she was as near giving it up, out of nonsensical complaisance!"
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Louisa, who was the most eager of the eager, having formed the resolution to go, and besides the pleasure of doing as she liked, being now armed with the <head>idea</head> of merit in maintaining her own way, bore down all the wishes of her father and mother for putting it off till summer; and to Lyme they were to go--Charles, Mary, Anne, Henrietta, Louisa, and Captain Wentworth
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="1"/>
<context>
noted down the names of those she recommended, and promised to procure and read them.When the evening was over, Anne could not but be amused at the <head>idea</head> of her coming to Lyme to preach patience and resignation to a young man whom she had never seen before; nor could she help fearing, on more serious reflection, that, like many other great moralists and preachers
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="1"/>
<context>
They had not a fault to find in him.  He had explained away all the appearance of neglect on his own side.  It had originated in misapprehension entirely.  He had never had an <head>idea</head> of throwing himself off; he had feared that he was thrown off, but knew not why, and delicacy had kept him silent.  Upon the hint of having spoken disrespectfully or carelessly of the family and the family honours, he was quite indignant
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Most earnestly did she wish that he might not be too nice, or too observant if Elizabeth were his object; and that Elizabeth was disposed to believe herself so, and that her friend Mrs Clay was encouraging the <head>idea</head>, seemed apparent by a glance or two between them, while Mr Elliot's frequent visits were talked of.Anne mentioned the glimpses she had had of him at Lyme, but without being much attended to
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="1"/>
<context>
he agreed to their being nothing in themselves, but still maintained that, as a family connexion, as good company, as those who would collect good company around them, they had their value.  Anne smiled and said, "My <head>idea</head> of good company, Mr Elliot, is the company of clever, well-informed people, who have a great deal of conversation; that is what I call good company." "You are mistaken," said he gently,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Anne was obliged to turn away, to rise, to walk to a distant table, and, leaning there in pretended employment, try to subdue the feelings this picture excited.  For a few moments her imagination and her heart were bewitched.  The <head>idea</head> of becoming what her mother had been; of having the precious name of "Lady Elliot" first revived in herself; of being restored to Kellynch, calling it her home again, her home for ever, was a charm which she could not immediately resist.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="1"/>
<context>
In her own room, she tried to comprehend it.  Well might Charles wonder how Captain Wentworth would feel!  Perhaps he had quitted the field, had given Louisa up, had ceased to love, had found he did not love her. She could not endure the <head>idea</head> of treachery or levity, or anything akin to ill usage between him and his friend.  She could not endure that such a friendship as theirs should be severed unfairly
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Louisa had fine naval fervour to begin with, and they would soon grow more alike. He would gain cheerfulness, and she would learn to be an enthusiast for Scott and Lord Byron; nay, that was probably learnt already; of course they had fallen in love over poetry.  The <head>idea</head> of Louisa Musgrove turned into a person of literary taste, and sentimental reflection was amusing, but she had no doubt of its being so.  The day at Lyme, the fall from the Cobb, might influence her health, her nerves, her courage, her character to the end of her life.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Benjamin Franklin was able to record in 1771 that America had twenty-five newspapers. Boston led with five. Philadelphia had three: two in English and one in German.The <head>idea</head> of printing, unlicensed by the government and uncontrolled by the church, was, however, slow in taking form. The founders of the American colonies had never known what it was to have the free and open publication of books, pamphlets, broadsides, and newspapers.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="2"/>
<context>
As more than 100,000 copies were scattered broadcast over the country, patriots exclaimed with Washington: "Sound doctrine and unanswerable reason!" Official support for the <head>idea</head> of independence began to come from many quarters. On the tenth of February, 1776, Gadsden, in the provincial convention of South Carolina, advocated a new constitution for the colony and absolute independence for all America.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="2"/>
<context>
state courts in passing upon the constitutionality of laws has remained unshaken.This doctrine was received by Jefferson and many of his followers with consternation. If the <head>idea</head> was sound, he exclaimed, "then indeed is our Constitution a complete _felo de se_ [legally, a suicide]. For, intending to establish three departments, coördinate and independent that they might check and balance one another, it has given, according to this opinion
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="2"/>
<context>
I believed with all my heart in real and thorough-going democracy and I wished to make the democracy industrial as well as political, although I had only partially formulated the method I believed we should follow." It is thus evident at least that he had departed a long way from the old <head>idea</head> of the government as nothing but a great policeman keeping order among the people in a struggle over the distribution of the nation's wealth and resources
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="2"/>
<context>
In this movement Governor La Follette of Wisconsin took the lead and his state was the first in the union to adopt the direct primary for state-wide purposes. The <head>idea</head> spread, rapidly in the West, more slowly in the East. The public, already angered against "the bosses," grasped eagerly at it. Governor Hughes in New York pressed it upon the unwilling legislature
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Mr. Bryce had remarked, was the one conspicuous failure in America. This sharp thrust, though resented by some, was accepted as a warning by others. Many prescriptions were offered by doctors of the body politic. Chief among them was the <head>idea</head> of simplifying the city government so that the light of public scrutiny could shine through it. "Let us elect only a few men and make them clearly responsible for the city government!" was the new cry in municipal reform. So, many city councils were reduced in size
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="2"/>
<context>
nominated a candidate for President, launched into a national campaign, and called upon trade unionists to desert the older parties and enter its fold.The socialistic <head>idea</head>, introduced into national politics in 1892, had been long in germination. Before the Civil War, a number of reformers, including Nathaniel Hawthorne, Horace Greeley, and Wendell Phillips, deeply moved by the poverty of the great industrial cities
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="2"/>
<context>
There were positive proofs that organized labor had obtained a large share of power in the councils of the country.If the interference of the government with business and labor represented a departure from the old <head>idea</head> of "the less government the better," what can be said of a large body of laws affecting the rights of states? The prohibition of child labor everywhere was one indication of the new tendency
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The busy, throbbing life in these countless centers of the Roman world has long since been stilled. The cities themselves, in many instances, have utterly disappeared. Yet the forms of municipal government, together with the Roman <head>idea</head> of a free, self-governing city, never wholly died out. Some of the most important cities which flourished in southern and western Europe during the later Middle Ages preserved clear traces of their ancient Roman origin
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Trade and travel united the provinces with one another and with Rome. The worship of the Caesars dimmed the luster of all local worships and kept constantly before men's minds the <head>idea</head> of Rome and of her mighty emperors. Last, but not least important, was the fusion of alien peoples through intermarriage with Roman soldiers and colonists.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The empire of Charlemagne, restored by Otto the Great, came to be called in later centuries the "Holy Roman Empire." The title points to the <head>idea</head> of a world monarchy--the Roman Empire--and a world religion--Roman Christianity--united in one institution. This magnificent idea was never fully realized.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="2"/>
<context>
The Roman genius for law and government found a new expression in the creation of the papal power. The true successors of the ancient Roman statesmen were the popes of the Middle Ages. The <head>idea</head> of Rome, of her universality and of her eternity, lived on in the Roman Church.The Roman Church, as the successor of the Roman Empire in the West, formed the chief center of civilization during the earlier part of the Middle Ages.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the idea came to him that much of the world remained undiscovered and that the distant East could be reached by a shorter route than that which led around AfricaColumbus was a well-read man, and in Aristotle, Ptolemy, and other ancient authorities he found apparent confirmation of his grand <head>idea</head>. Columbus also owned a printed copy of Marco Polo's book, and from his comments, written on the margin, we know how interested he was in Polo's statements referring to Cathay and Cipango
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the coach was beginning to be listened for, when the youngest Miss Musgrove walked in.  That she was coming to apologize, and that they should have to spend the evening by themselves, was the first black <head>idea</head>; and Mary was quite ready to be affronted, when Louisa made all right by saying, that she only came on foot,to leave more room for the harp, which was bringing in the carriage
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="2"/>
<context>
She had before conjectured him to be a stranger like themselves, and determined that a well-looking groom, who was strolling about near the two inns as they came back, should be his servant. Both master and man being in mourning assisted the <head>idea</head>. It was now proved that he belonged to the same inn as themselves; and this second meeting, short as it was, also proved again by the gentleman's looks, that he thought hers very lovely, and by the readiness and propriety of his apologies
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Anne avoided a direct reply, but it was just the circumstance which she considered as not merely unnecessary to be communicated, but as what ought to be suppressed.  The offence which had been given her father, many years back, she knew; Elizabeth's particular share in it she suspected; and that Mr Elliot's <head>idea</head> always produced irritation in both was beyond a doubt.  Mary never wrote to Bath herself; all the toil of keeping up a slow and unsatisfactory correspondence with Elizabeth fell on Anne.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="2"/>
<context>
here were many other men about him, many groups walking the same way, but there was no mistaking him. She looked instinctively at Lady Russell; but not from any mad <head>idea</head> of her recognising him so soon as she did herself.  No, it was not to be supposed that Lady Russell would perceive him till they were nearly opposite.  She looked at her however, from time to time
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="3"/>
<context>
forerunner of the University of Pennsylvania, organized by Benjamin Franklin, reflected the spirit of toleration by giving representation on the board of trustees to several religious sects. It was Franklin's <head>idea</head> that his college should prepare young men to serve in public office as leaders of the people and ornaments to their country.=Self-education in America.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="3"/>
<context>
the male citizens of said state, twenty-one years old and upward, of whatever race, color, or previous condition, ... except such as may be disfranchised for participation in the rebellion or for felony at common law." This was the death knell to the <head>idea</head> that the leaders of the Confederacy and their white supporters might be permitted to share in the establishment of the new order. Power was thus arbitrarily thrust into the hands of the newly emancipated male negroes and the handful of whites who could show a record of loyalty
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="3"/>
<context>
At this juncture the presidential campaign of 1920 opened. The Republicans, while condemning the terms of the proposed League, endorsed the general <head>idea</head> of an international agreement to prevent war. Their candidate, Senator Warren G. Harding of Ohio, maintained a similar position without saying definitely whether the League devised at Paris could be recast in such a manner as to meet his requirements
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Some Oriental peoples kept the primitive belief that after death all men, good and bad alike, suffered the same fate. The Babylonians supposed that the souls of the departed passed a cheerless existence in a gloomy and Hebrew underworld. The early Hebrew <head>idea</head> of Sheol, "the land of darkness and the shadow of death," [16] was very similar. Such thoughts of the future life left nothing for either fear or hope. In later times, however, the Hebrews came to believe in the resurrection of the dead and the last judgment, conceptions afterwards adopted by Christianity.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="3"/>
<context>
A mosaic dating from 547 A.D., in the church of San Vitale, Ravenna. It shows the emperor (in the center) with a bishop, his suite and imperial guards. The picture probably gives us a fair <head>idea</head> of Justinian's appearance, though it represents him as somewhat younger than he was at the time.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="3"/>
<context>
It was not uncommon for a Viking chieftain, after his days of sea-roving had ended, to be buried in his ship, over which a grave chamber, covered with earth, would be erected. The discovery of several of these burial ships enables us to form a good <head>idea</head> of Viking vessels. The largest of them might reach a length of seventy feet and hold as many as one hundred and twenty men. A fleet of the Northmen, carrying several thousand warriors, mail-clad and armed with spears, swords, and battle-axes, was indeed formidable
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="3"/>
<context>
The new theory met much opposition, not only in the universities, which clung to the time-honored Ptolemaic system, but also among theologians, who thought that it contradicted many statements in the Bible. Moreover, people could not easily reconcile themselves to the <head>idea</head> that the earth, instead of being the center of the universe, is only one member of the solar system, that it is, in fact, only a mere speck of cosmic dust.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Then the Portuguese turned southward along the unchartered African coast. In 1445 A.D. they got as far as Cape Verde, or "Green Cape," so called because of its luxuriant vegetation. The discovery was important, for it disposed of the <head>idea</head> that the Sahara desert extended indefinitely to the south. Sierra Leone, which the Carthaginian Hanno [11] had probably visited, was reached in 1462 A.D., two years after Prince Henry's death. Soon Portuguese sailors found the great bend of the African coast formed by the gulf of Guinea.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="3"/>
<context>
It practically settled the religious question, for it allowed Calvinists in Germany to enjoy the same privileges as Lutherans and also withdrew the Edict of Restitution. Nothing was said in the treaties about liberty of conscience, but from this time the <head>idea</head> that religious differences should be settled by force gradually passed away from the minds of men.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="3"/>
<context>
As Mr Shepherd perceived that this connexion of the Crofts did them no service with Sir Walter, he mentioned it no more; returning, with all his zeal, to dwell on the circumstances more indisputably in their favour; their age, and number, and fortune; the high <head>idea</head> they had formed of Kellynch Hall, and extreme solicitude for the advantage of renting it; making it appear as if they ranked nothing beyond the happiness of being the tenants of Sir Walter Elliot.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="3"/>
<context>
That was a point which Anne had not been able to avoid suspecting before; and instead of drawing the same conclusion as Mary, from the present course of events, they served only to confirm the <head>idea</head> of his having felt some dawning of tenderness toward herself.  She did not mean, however, to derive much more from it to gratify her vanity, than Mary might have allowed.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Sophy and I cannot help thinking Frederick's manners better than his. There is something about Frederick more to our taste."Anne was caught.  She had only meant to oppose the too common <head>idea</head> of spirit and gentleness being incompatible with each other, not at all to represent Captain Benwick's manners as the very best that could possibly be; and, after a little hesitation, she was beginning to say
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="3"/>
<context>
"No, no, some time or other, perhaps, but not now.  He would mention no names now; but such, he could assure her, had been the fact. He had many years ago received such a description of Miss Anne Elliot as had inspired him with the highest <head>idea</head> of her merit, and excited the warmest curiosity to know her."Anne could think of no one so likely to have spoken with partiality of her many years ago as the Mr Wentworth of Monkford, Captain Wentworth's brother
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="4"/>
<context>
The characteristic works of Egyptian architecture are the tombs of the kings and the temples of the gods. The picture of the great structure at Thebes, which Rameses II completed, [17] will give some <head>idea</head> of an Egyptian temple with its gateways, open courts, obelisks, and statues.Found in a tomb near Memphis. The statue, which belongs to the age of the pyramid kings, represents a bustling, active, middle-class official
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Many modern scholars, however, consider them the work of several generations of poets. The references in the _Iliad_ and the _Odyssey_ to industry, social life, law, government, and religion give us some <head>idea</head> of the culture which the historic Greeks received as their inheritance. The Greeks as described in the Homeric epics were in a transitional stage between the life of shepherds and that of farmers
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Most of the municipalities enjoyed an abundant supply of water, and some had good sewer systems. The larger towns had well-paved, though narrow, streets. Pompeii, a small place of scarcely thirty thousand inhabitants, still exists to give us an <head>idea</head> of the appearance of one of these ancient cities. And what we find at Pompeii was repeated on a more splendid scale in hundreds of places from the Danube to the Nile, from Britain to Arabia.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="4"/>
<context>
But the better class of Roman houses, such as some of those excavated at Pompeii, [11] followed Greek designs in many respects. The Pompeian remains, therefore, will give some <head>idea</head> of the sort of residence occupied by a well-to-do citizen of Athens or Rome.The visitor at one of these ancient houses first entered a small vestibule
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="4"/>
<context>
The existing monuments of Greek architecture--chiefly ruined temples-- afford some <head>idea</head> of its leading characteristics. The building materials were limestone and white marble. The blocks of stone were not bound together by cement, but by metal clamps which held them in a firm grip
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="4"/>
<context>
here is less accuracy in the masonry fitting and far less careful attention to details of construction. A frequent departure from Greek models is found in the restriction of the rows of pillars to the front of the building, while the sides and rear are lined with "engaged" columns to give the <head>idea</head> of a colonnade. [34] More characteristically Roman are vaulted temples, such as the Pantheon, [35] where the circular dome is faced with a Greek portico
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Many buildings erected in the imperial age have also disappeared, because in medieval and modern times the inhabitants of Rome used the ancient edifices as quarries. The existing monuments give only a faint <head>idea</head> of the former magnificence of the capital city. The city of Rome lies on the Tiber. Where the river approaches Rome it makes two sharp turns, first to the west and then to the east.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Near it and in the foreground are several columns in the Corinthian style, belonging to a temple built by Vespasian.These ruined monuments, these empty foundations and lonely pillars, afford little <head>idea</head> of all the wealth of architecture that once adorned this spot. Here stood the circular shrine of Vesta, [62] guarding the altar and its ever-blazing fire. Here was the temple of Concord, famous in Roman history
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="4"/>
<context>
It is clear that he greatly underestimated the distance westward between Europe and Asia. The error was natural enough, for Ptolemy had reckoned the earth's circumference to be about one-sixth less than it is, and Marco Polo had given an exaggerated <head>idea</head> of the distance to which Asia extended on the east. When Columbus set out on his voyage, he firmly believed that a journey of four thousand miles would bring him to Cipango
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="4"/>
<context>
"The day has produced some effects however; has had some consequences which must be considered as the very reverse of frightful. When you had the presence of mind to suggest that Benwick would be the properest person to fetch a surgeon, you could have little <head>idea</head> of his being eventually one of those most concerned in her recovery." "Certainly I could have none.  But it appears--I should hope it would be a very happy match.  There are on both sides good principles and good temper."
</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
