<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<corpus lang='english'>

<lexelt item="tell">

<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
is used to see. Whenever James goes over to see his daughter, you know, she will be hearing of us. He will be able to <head>tell</head> her how we all are."  Emma spared no exertions to maintain this happier flow of ideas, and hoped, by the help of backgammon, to get
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
she must be a gainer." "Well," said Emma, willing to let it pass--"you want to hear about the wedding; and I shall be happy to <head>tell</head> you, for we all behaved charmingly.  Every body was punctual, every body in their best looks: not a tear, and hardly a long face to
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
done; for Harriet every thing. Her first attempts at usefulness were in an endeavour to find out who were the parents, but Harriet could not <head>tell</head>  She was ready to tell every thing in her power, but on this subject questions were vain. Emma was obliged to fancy what she liked--but
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
Her first attempts at usefulness were in an endeavour to find out who were the parents, but Harriet could not tell. She was ready to <head>tell</head> every thing in her power, but on this subject questions were vain. Emma was obliged to fancy what she liked--but she could never believe that
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
_she_ should not have discovered the truth. Harriet had no penetration. She had been satisfied to hear and believe just what Mrs. Goddard chose to <head>tell</head> her; and looked no farther.  Mrs. Goddard, and the teachers, and the girls and the affairs of the school in general, formed naturally a great 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
shall come forth out of thine own bowels shall be thine heir. And he brought him forth abroad, and said, Look now toward heaven, and <head>tell</head> the stars, if thou be able to number th and he said unto him, So shall thy seed be. And he believed in the LORD;</context>
</instance>

<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="Assure"/>
<context>
weig and we have brought it again in our hand. And other money have we brought down in our hands to buy food: we cannot <head>tell</head> who put our money in our sacks. And he said, Peace be to you, fear not: your God, and the God of your father, hath
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
him, "We have dreamed a dream, and there is no one who can interpret it." Joseph said to them, "Don't interpretations belong to God? Please <head>tell</head> it to me." The chief cupbearer told his dream to Joseph, and said to him, "In my dream, behold, a vine was in front of
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
that you have deceived me, and carried away my daughters like captives of the sword? Why did you flee secretly, and deceive me, and didn't <head>tell</head> me, that I might have sent you away with mirth and with songs, with tambourine and with harp; and didn't allow me to kiss my
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
distress of his soul, when he begged us, and we wouldn't listen. Therefore this distress has come upon us." Reuben answered them, saying, "Didn't I <head>tell</head> you, saying, 'Don't sin against the child,' and you wouldn't listen? Therefore also, behold, his blood is required." They didn't know that Joseph understood them;
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
For she is a man's wife." Now Abimelech had not come near her. He said, "Lord, will you kill even a righteous nation? Didn't he <head>tell</head> me, 'She is my sister?'  She, even she herself, said, 'He is my brother.'  In the integrity of my heart and the innocence of my
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
have sojourned with Laban, and stayed there until n And I have oxen, and asses, flocks, and menservants, and womenservan and I have sent to <head>tell</head> my lord, that I may find grace in thy sight. And the messengers returned to Jacob, saying, We came to thy brother Esau, and also
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
hear with thine ears. 3:11 And go, get thee to them of the captivity, unto the children of thy people, and speak unto them, and <head>tell</head> them, Thus saith the Lord GOD; whether they will hear, or whether they will forbear.  3:12 Then the spirit took me up, and I heard
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="confused"/>
<context>
ever since I knew you. Yes, Harriet, just so long have I been wanting the very circumstance to happen what has happened. I could never <head>tell</head> whether an attachment between you and Mr. Elton were most desirable or most natural. Its probability and its eligibility have really so equalled each other! 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
a well of water, which Abimelech's servants had violently taken away. And Abimelech said, I wot not who hath done this thing; neither did'nt they <head>tell</head> me, neither yet heard I of it, but to day. And Abraham took sheep and oxen, and gave them unto Abimelech; and both of them
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="let something be known "/>
<context>
Laban had gone to shear his sheep: and Rachel stole the teraphim that were her father's. Jacob deceived Laban the Syrian, in that he didn't <head>tell</head> him that he was running away. So he fled with all that he had.  He rose up, passed over the River, and set his face
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
all of the evil which we did to him." They sent a message to Joseph, saying, "Your father commanded before he died, saying, 'You shall <head>tell</head> Joseph, "Now please forgive the disobedience of your brothers, and their sin, because they did evil to you."' Now, please forgive the disobedience of the
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
a father to Pharaoh, lord of all his house, and ruler over all the land of Egypt. Hurry, and go up to my father, and <head>tell</head> him, 'This is what your son Joseph says, "God has made me lord of all Egypt. Come down to me.  Don't wait. You shall dwell
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
love, even Isaac, and go into the land of Moriah. Offer him there for a burnt offering on one of the mountains which I will <head>tell</head> you of." Abraham rose early in the morning, and saddled his donkey, and took two of his young men with him, and Isaac his son.
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
that you are still alive." Joseph said to his brothers, and to his father's house, "I will go up, and speak with Pharaoh, and will <head>tell</head> him, 'My brothers, and my father's house, who were in the land of Canaan, have come to me. These men are shepherds, for they have
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
name will no longer be called Jacob, but Israel; for you have fought with God and with men, and have prevailed." Jacob asked him, "Please <head>tell</head> me your name." He said, "Why is it that you ask what my name is?" He blessed him there. Jacob called the name of the
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
was not for the drawback of her illness--but I am afraid we must expect to see her grown thin, and looking very poorly. I must <head>tell</head> you what an unlucky thing happened to me, as to that. I always make a point of reading Jane's letters through to myself first, before 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
"What deed is this that you have done? Don't you know that such a man as I can indeed divine?" Judah said, "What will we <head>tell</head> my lord?  What will we speak? Or how will we clear ourselves?  God has found out the iniquity of your servants.  Behold, we are my
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
front of him to Esau, his brother, to the land of Seir, the field of Edom. He commanded them, saying, "This is what you shall <head>tell</head> my lord, Esau:  'This is what your servant, Jacob, says. I have lived as a foreigner with Laban, and stayed until now. I have oxen,
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
was given, Emma felt that she could not now shew greater kindness than in listening; and Harriet, unchecked, ran eagerly through what she had to <head>tell</head>  "She had set out from Mrs. Goddard's half an hour ago--she had been afraid it would rain--she had been afraid it would pour down every 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
the hand of the Amorite with my sword and with my bow." Jacob called to his sons, and said: "Gather yourselves together, that I may <head>tell</head> you that which will happen to you in the days to come. Assemble yourselves, and hear, you sons of Jacob. Listen to Israel, your father.
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
a well of water, which Abimelech's servants had violently taken away. And Abimelech said, I wot not who hath done this thing; neither didst thou <head>tell</head> me, neither yet heard I of it, but to day. And Abraham took sheep and oxen, and gave them unto Abimelech; and both of them
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="Assure"/>
<context>
you might be very much at a loss, and it is a very dirty walk, unless you keep on the footpath; but my coachman can <head>tell</head> you where you had best cross the street."  Mr. Frank Churchill still declined it, looking as serious as he could, and his father gave his 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
no where, and therefore must decline their obliging invitation; beginning with my _compliments_, of course. But you will do every thing right. I need not <head>tell</head> you what is to be done.  We must remember to let James know that the carriage will be wanted on Tuesday.  I shall have no 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
the new approach was made; but still I have no doubt that James will take you very safely. And when you get there, you must <head>tell</head> him at what time you would have him come for you again; and you had better name an early hour. You will not like staying 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
in her's. I do not require you to adopt all my suspicions, though you make so noble a profession of doing it, but I honestly <head>tell</head> you what they are."  "And, upon my word, they have an air of great probability. Mr. Dixon's preference of her music to her friend's, I 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
thing. My dear Emma, I am longing to talk to you. I have been making discoveries and forming plans, just like yourself, and I must <head>tell</head> them while the idea is fresh. Do you know how Miss Bates and her niece came here?"  "How?--They were invited, were not they?"  "Oh! yes--but 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
merely its probability." "I see no probability in it, unless you have any better foundation than what you mention. His good-nature, his humanity, as I <head>tell</head> you, would be quite enough to account for the horses.  He has a great regard for the Bateses, you know, independent of Jane Fairfax-- and 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
pleasure," said he, in rather a low voice, "coming at least ten minutes earlier than I had calculated. You find me trying to be useful; <head>tell</head> me if you think I shall succeed."  "What!" said Mrs. Weston, "have not you finished it yet? you would not earn a very good livelihood 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
them talk of such a wild thing. Pray do not let them talk of it. That young man (speaking lower) is very thoughtless. Do not <head>tell</head> his father, but that young man is not quite the thing. He has been opening the doors very often this evening, and keeping them open 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
know which arrangement our guests in general would like best. To do what would be most generally pleasing must be our object--if one could but <head>tell</head> what that would be."  "Yes, very true," cried Frank, "very true.  You want your neighbours' opinions.  I do not wonder at you.  If one could 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
of any use." "You will get nothing to the purpose from Miss Bates," said Emma. "She will be all delight and gratitude, but she will <head>tell</head> you nothing. She will not even listen to your questions.  I see no advantage in consulting Miss Bates."  "But she is so amusing, so extremely 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
She has been so kind as to promise it. Oh! the blessing of a female correspondent, when one is really interested in the absent!--she will <head>tell</head> me every thing. In her letters I shall be at dear Highbury again."  A very friendly shake of the hand, a very earnest "Good-bye," closed 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
sign I was not there to take care of you." Jane very patiently assured her that she had not caught any cold. "Oh! do not <head>tell</head> _me_.  You really are a very sad girl, and do not know how to take care of yourself.--To the post-office indeed! Mrs. Weston, did you 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
Well, what do you say to it?--I always told you he would be here again soon, did not I?--Anne, my dear, did not I always <head>tell</head> you so, and you would not believe me?--In town next week, you see--at the latest, I dare say; for _she_ is as impatient as the 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="Assure"/>
<context>
Mr. Frank Churchill was so extremely-- and there was a mat to step upon--I shall never forget his extreme politeness.--Oh! Mr. Frank Churchill, I must <head>tell</head> you my mother's spectacles have never been in fault since; the rivet never came out again.  My mother often talks of your good-nature. Does not 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
said Emma in a whisper. "Not at all." "You are ungrateful." "Ungrateful!--What do you mean?" Then changing from a frown to a smile--"No, do not <head>tell</head> me--I do not want to know what you mean.-- Where is my father?--When are we to begin dancing?"  Emma could hardly understand him; he seemed 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
and who were your partners. `Oh!' said I, `I shall not forestall Jane; I left her dancing with Mr. George Otway; she will love to <head>tell</head> you all about it herself to-morrow: her first partner was Mr. Elton, I do not know who will ask her next, perhaps Mr. William Cox.' 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
only said, "I shall not scold you. I leave you to your own reflections." "Can you trust me with such flatterers?--Does my vain spirit ever <head>tell</head> me I am wrong?"  "Not your vain spirit, but your serious spirit.--If one leads you wrong, I am sure the other tells you of it."  
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
parcel in her hand, and after sitting down and hesitating, thus began: "Miss Woodhouse--if you are at leisure--I have something that I should like to <head>tell</head> you--a sort of confession to make--and then, you know, it will be over."  Emma was a good deal surprized; but begged her to speak. There 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
looking for her shawl--Frank Churchill was looking also--it was growing dusk, and the room was in confusion; and how they parted, Mr. Knightley could not <head>tell</head>  He remained at Hartfield after all the rest, his thoughts full of what he had seen; so full, that when the candles came to assist 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="Assure"/>
<context>
weig and we have brought it again in our hand. And other money have we brought down in our hands to buy food: we cannot <head>tell</head> who put our money in our sacks. And he said, Peace be to you, fear not: your God, and the God of your father, hath
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
two letters!--express perfection! I am sure I do not know." "Ah! you will never guess. You, (to Emma), I am certain, will never guess.--I will <head>tell</head> you.--M. and A.--Em-ma.--Do you understand?"  Understanding and gratification came together.  It might be a very indifferent piece of wit, but Emma found a great deal 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
by _your_ treatment of her.--This is not pleasant to you, Emma--and it is very far from pleasant to me; but I must, I will,--I will <head>tell</head> you truths while I can; satisfied with proving myself your friend by very faithful counsel, and trusting that you will some time or other do 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
scheme to Box Hill was in Emma's thoughts all the evening. How it might be considered by the rest of the party, she could not <head>tell</head>  They, in their different homes, and their different ways, might be looking back on it with pleasure; but in her view it was a morning 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
without a heart. She hoped no one could have said to her, "How could you be so unfeeling to your father?-- I must, I will <head>tell</head> you truths while I can."  Miss Bates should never again--no, never!  If attention, in future, could do away the past, she might hope to be 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
have been thinking of it some little time." Emma was sure he had not forgiven her; he looked unlike himself. Time, however, she thought, would <head>tell</head> him that they ought to be friends again.  While he stood, as if meaning to go, but not going-- her father began his inquiries.  "Well, 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
Do not be impatient, Emma; it will all come out too soon." "Break it to me," cried Emma, standing still with terror.-- "Good God!--Mr. Weston, <head>tell</head> me at once.--Something has happened in Brunswick Square.  I know it has.  Tell me, I charge you tell me this moment what it is."  "No, 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
standing still with terror.-- "Good God!--Mr. Weston, tell me at once.--Something has happened in Brunswick Square. I know it has. Tell me, I charge you <head>tell</head> me this moment what it is."  "No, indeed you are mistaken."--  "Mr. Weston do not trifle with me.--Consider how many of my dearest friends are 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
hear?" "So far as that it relates to Mr. Frank Churchill, I do guess." "You are right. It does relate to him, and I will <head>tell</head> you directly;" (resuming her work, and seeming resolved against looking up.) "He has been here this very morning, on a most extraordinary errand. It is 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
as steady as her words. "That you may have less difficulty in believing this boast, of my present perfect indifference," she continued, "I will farther <head>tell</head> you, that there was a period in the early part of our acquaintance, when I did like him, when I was very much disposed to 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
to please, as he certainly did--to distinguish any one young woman with persevering attention, as he certainly did--while he really belonged to another?--How could he <head>tell</head> what mischief he might be doing?-- How could he tell that he might not be making me in love with him?-- very wrong, very wrong 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
woman with persevering attention, as he certainly did--while he really belonged to another?--How could he tell what mischief he might be doing?-- How could he <head>tell</head> that he might not be making me in love with him?-- very wrong, very wrong indeed."  "From something that he said, my dear Emma, I 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="Assure"/>
<context>
but was in such a hurry to get back to his uncle, to whom he is just now more necessary than ever, that, as I <head>tell</head> you, he could stay with us but a quarter of an hour.-- He was very much agitated--very much, indeed--to a degree that made him appear 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
ought to have prevented them.--She felt that she had been risking her friend's happiness on most insufficient grounds. Common sense would have directed her to <head>tell</head> Harriet, that she must not allow herself to think of him, and that there were five hundred chances to one against his ever caring for
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
secret; and, therefore, I should not think of mentioning it to any body but you, but he said you knew it." "What did Mr. Weston <head>tell</head> you?"--said Emma, still perplexed.  "Oh! he told me all about it; that Jane Fairfax and Mr. Frank Churchill are to be married, and that they 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
ask me what is the point of envy.--You are determined, I see, to have no curiosity.--You are wise--but _I_ cannot be wise. Emma, I must <head>tell</head> you what you will not ask, though I may wish it unsaid the next moment."  "Oh! then, don't speak it, don't speak it," she eagerly 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
my opinion of any thing that you may have in contemplation--as a friend, indeed, you may command me.--I will hear whatever you like. I will <head>tell</head> you exactly what I think."  "As a friend!"--repeated Mr. Knightley.--"Emma, that I fear is a word--No, I have no wish--Stay, yes, why should I hesitate?-- 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
overpowered her. "My dearest Emma," said he, "for dearest you will always be, whatever the event of this hour's conversation, my dearest, most beloved Emma-- <head>tell</head> me at once.  Say `No,' if it is to be said."-- She could really say nothing.--"You are silent," he cried, with great animation; "absolutely silent! 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
you, and lectured you, and you have borne it as no other woman in England would have borne it.-- Bear with the truths I would <head>tell</head> you now, dearest Emma, as well as you have borne with them.  The manner, perhaps, may have as little to recommend them.  God knows, I 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
much beyond my power of doing justice to. You will soon, I earnestly hope, know her thoroughly yourself.-- No description can describe her. She must <head>tell</head> you herself what she is-- yet not by word, for never was there a human creature who would so designedly suppress her own merit.--Since I 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
patience with me, I shall soon have done.-- She closed with this offer, resolving to break with me entirely, and wrote the next day to <head>tell</head> me that we never were to meet again.-- _She_ _felt_ _the_ _engagement_ _to_ _be_ _a_ _source_ _of_ _repentance_ _and_ _misery_ _to_ _each_:  _she_ _dissolved_ _it_.--This 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
Highbury the next morning, and satisfied himself on that point. He told her the news. Was not she like a daughter, his eldest daughter?--he must <head>tell</head> her; and Miss Bates being present, it passed, of course, to Mrs. Cole, Mrs. Perry, and Mrs. Elton, immediately afterwards.  It was no more than 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
thoughts were put by. After the first chat of pleasure he was silent; and then, in a graver tone, began with, "I have something to <head>tell</head> you, Emma; some news."  "Good or bad?" said she, quickly, looking up in his face.  "I do not know which it ought to be called."  
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
you heard from her yourself this morning?" cried he. "You have, I believe, and know the whole." "No, I have not; I know nothing; pray <head>tell</head> me."  "You are prepared for the worst, I see--and very bad it is. Harriet Smith marries Robert Martin."  Emma gave a start, which did not 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
leaning down her face, and concealing all the exquisite feelings of delight and entertainment which she knew she must be expressing, she added, "Well, now <head>tell</head> me every thing; make this intelligible to me.  How, where, when?--Let me know it all. I never was more surprized--but it does not make me 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
caught through the blind, of two figures passing near the window. "It is Frank and Miss Fairfax," said Mrs. Weston. "I was just going to <head>tell</head> you of our agreeable surprize in seeing him arrive this morning.  He stays till to-morrow, and Miss Fairfax has been persuaded to spend the day 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
was a source of high entertainment to you, to feel that you were taking us all in.--Perhaps I am the readier to suspect, because, to <head>tell</head> you the truth, I think it might have been some amusement to myself in the same situation.  I think there is a little likeness between 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
is used to see. Whenever James goes over to see his daughter, you know, she will be hearing of us. He will be able to <head>tell</head> her how we all are."  Emma spared no exertions to maintain this happier flow of ideas, and hoped, by the help of backgammon, to get 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
she must be a gainer." "Well," said Emma, willing to let it pass--"you want to hear about the wedding; and I shall be happy to <head>tell</head> you, for we all behaved charmingly.  Every body was punctual, every body in their best looks: not a tear, and hardly a long face to 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
done; for Harriet every thing. Her first attempts at usefulness were in an endeavour to find out who were the parents, but Harriet could not <head>tell</head>  She was ready to tell every thing in her power, but on this subject questions were vain. Emma was obliged to fancy what she liked--but 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
Her first attempts at usefulness were in an endeavour to find out who were the parents, but Harriet could not tell. She was ready to <head>tell</head> every thing in her power, but on this subject questions were vain. Emma was obliged to fancy what she liked--but she could never believe that 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
and carried away my daughters, as captives taken with the sword? Wherefore didst thou flee away secretly, and steal away from me; and didst not <head>tell</head> me, that I might have sent thee away with mirth, and with songs, with tabret, and with harp? And hast not suffered me to kiss
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
and get possessions in it." Shechem said to her father and to her brothers, "Let me find favor in your eyes, and whatever you will <head>tell</head> me I will give. Ask me a great amount for a dowry, and I will give whatever you ask of me, but give me the
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
poverty. And, behold, your eyes see, and the eyes of my brother Benjamin, that it is my mouth that speaketh unto you. And ye shall <head>tell</head> my father of all my glory in Egypt, and of all that ye have seen; and ye shall haste and bring down my father hither.
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
us, Ye shall not see my face, except your brother be with you. And Israel said, Wherefore dealt ye so ill with me, as to <head>tell</head> the man whether ye had yet a brother? And they said, The man asked us straitly of our state, and of our kindred, saying, Is
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
unto him, We have dreamed a dream, and there is no interpreter of it. And Joseph said unto them, Do not interpretations belong to God? <head>tell</head> me them, I pray you. And the chief butler told his dream to Joseph, and said to him, In my dream, behold, a vine was
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
for contradiction, and therefore said nothing. He presently added, with a smile, "I do not pretend to fix on times or places, but I must <head>tell</head> you that I have good reason to believe your little friend will soon hear of something to her advantage."  "Indeed! how so? of what sort?"  
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="Assure"/>
<context>
because of a water well, which Abimelech's servants had violently taken away. Abimelech said, "I don't know who has done this thing. Neither did you <head>tell</head> me, neither did I hear of it, until today." Abraham took sheep and oxen, and gave them to Abimelech. Those two made a covenant. Abraham
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
him, and, behold, he was wandering in the fie and the man asked him, saying, What seekest thou? And he said, I seek my brethren: <head>tell</head> me, I pray thee, where they feed their flocks. And the man said, They are departed hence; for I heard them say, Let us go
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
when she considered that Mr. Knightley could not have observed him as she had done, neither with the interest, nor (she must be allowed to <head>tell</head> herself, in spite of Mr. Knightley's pretensions) with the skill of such an observer on such a question as herself, that he had spoken it 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
<context>
that you have."' Behold, your eyes see, and the eyes of my brother Benjamin, that it is my mouth that speaks to you. You shall <head>tell</head> my father of all my glory in Egypt, and of all that you have seen.  You shall hurry and bring my father down here." He
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
have lived as a foreigner with Laban, and stayed until now. I have oxen, donkeys, flocks, male servants, and female servants. I have sent to <head>tell</head> my lord, that I may find favor in your sight.'" The messengers returned to Jacob, saying, "We came to your brother Esau.  Not only that,
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
strong expectation of his coming soon after the marriage, but it ended in nothing; and I have not heard him mentioned lately." "But you should <head>tell</head> them of the letter, my dear," said her father. "He wrote a letter to poor Mrs. Weston, to congratulate her, and a very proper, handsome 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="Assure"/>
<context>
was. She shewed it to me. I thought it very well done of him indeed. Whether it was his own idea you know, one cannot <head>tell</head>  He is but young, and his uncle, perhaps--"  "My dear papa, he is three-and-twenty. You forget how time passes."  "Three-and-twenty!--is he indeed?--Well, I could not
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
in the right way to take my master's brother's daughter unto his son. And now if ye will deal kindly and truly with my master, <head>tell</head> and if not, tell me; that I may turn to the right hand, or to the left. Then Laban and Bethuel answered and said, The
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
golden earring of half a shekel weight, and two bracelets for her hands of ten shekels weight of gold; And said, Whose daughter art thou? <head>tell</head> me, I pray thee: is there room in thy father's house for us to lodge in? And she said unto him, I am the daughter
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
plagues because of Sarai Abram's wife. And Pharaoh called Abram and said, What is this that thou hast done unto me? why didst thou not <head>tell</head> me that she was thy wife? Why saidst thou, She is my sister? so I might have taken her to me to wife now therefore
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
of the Philistines unto Gerar. And the LORD appeared unto him, and said, Go not down into Egypt; dwell in the land which I shall <head>tell</head> thee  Sojourn in this land, and I will be with thee, and will bless thee; for unto thee, and unto thy seed, I will give
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
abode with him the space of a month. And Laban said unto Jacob, Because thou art my brother, shouldest thou therefore serve me for nought? <head>tell</head> me, what shall thy wages be? And Laban had two daughters: the name of the elder was Leah, and the name of the younger was
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
hand of the Amorite with my sword and with my bow. And Jacob called unto his sons, and said, Gather yourselves together, that I may <head>tell</head> you that which shall befall you in the last days. Gather yourselves together, and hear, ye sons of Jacob; and hearken unto Israel your father.
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
diffident. I do not see it." "My dear Emma," said he, moving from his chair into one close by her, "you are not going to <head>tell</head> me, I hope, that you had not a pleasant evening."  "Oh! no; I was pleased with my own perseverance in asking questions; and amused to 
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
was given, Emma felt that she could not now shew greater kindness than in listening; and Harriet, unchecked, ran eagerly through what she had to <head>tell</head>  "She had set out from Mrs. Goddard's half an hour ago--she had been afraid it would rain--she had been afraid it would pour down every
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="let something be known"/>
<context>
to take my master's brother's daughter unto his son. And now if ye will deal kindly and truly with my master, tell and if not, <head>tell</head> me; that I may turn to the right hand, or to the left. Then Laban and Bethuel answered and said, The thing proceedeth from the
</context>
</instance>

<instance id="100">
<answer instance="100" senseid="state_say"/>
<context>
lovest, and get thee into the land of Moriah; and offer him there for a burnt offering upon one of the mountains which I will <head>tell</head> thee of. And Abraham rose up early in the morning, and saddled his ass, and took two of his young men with him, and Isaac
</context>
<instance id="101">
    <answer instance="101" senseid="narrate_recite"/>
    <context>
        to Abimelech king of the Philistines, to Gerar. Yahweh appeared to him, and said, "Don't go down into Egypt. Live in the land I will <head>tell</head> you about. Sojourn in this land, and I will be with you, and will bless you. For to you, and to your seed, I will
    </context>
</instance>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>